listening part
one there are five parts to the test you
will hear each piece twice now look at
the instructions for part
one for each question choose the correct
answer look at question one
one how much will the woman pay for the
laptop can I help you uh yes uh I'd like
to buy a laptop for my son I'd like to
pay about
£600 this one's on sale at the moment
from
£750 it's now down to
£650 that's a good discount from
£750 I'll take it fine
now listen
again can I help you uh yes uh I'd like
to buy a laptop for my son I'd like to
pay about
£600 this one's on sale at the moment
from
£750 it's now down to 650 that's a good
discount from
£750 I'll take it
fine two what's Sue doing
now hi Sue what are you doing I was
studying but I've just finished at the
moment I'm watching my favorite nature
program what about you I'm doing my
college work do you want to go for a
walk later yes I'd love to go for a walk
great I'll come to your house at 700
now listen
again hi Sue what are you doing I was
studying but I've just finished at the
moment I'm watching my favorite nature
program what about you I'm doing my
college work do you want to go for a
walk later yes I'd love to go for a walk
great I'll come to your house at 7
three what has Tom just finished
doing hi Tom have you found our new
customer in Spain he's really nice hi
Rachel I'm going to do that next I've
just come out of a meeting with my
manager oh what was that about we were
talking about that email that I got
about maybe advertising on TV oh that's
interesting now listen
again hi Tom have you found our new
customer in Spain he's really nice hi
Rachel I'm going to do that next I've
just come out of a meeting with my
manager oh what was that about we were
talking about that email that I got
about maybe advertising on TV oh
that's
interesting four who is Dan meeting at
the
weekend what are you doing at the
weekend Dan I'm meeting my friends Rob
and Sarah is Sarah your friend with long
Fair hair that's Rosa Sarah's got dark
hair and she wears glasses and robs her
younger brother but he's taller than her
he's still at school he's got short dark
hair and glasses ah yes I remember
now now listen
again what are you doing at the weekend
Dan I'm meeting my friends Rob and Sarah
is Sarah your friend with long Fair hair
that's Rosa Sarah's got dark hair and
she wears glasses and robs her younger
brother but he's taller than her he's
still at school he's got short dark hair
and glasses ah yes I remember
now five what present is the boy going
to give
Tina what are you going to buy Tina for
her birthday I thought about per perfume
but I'm not sure which one she likes her
favorite writer has just written a new
horror story so I'll get her that good
idea I've bought her some earrings more
jewelry doesn't she have enough earrings
no now listen
again what are you going to buy Tina for
her birthday I thought about perfect
fume but I'm not sure which one she
likes her favorite writer has just
written a new horror story so I'll get
her that good idea I've bought her some
earrings more jewelry doesn't she have
enough earrings
no that is the end of part one
test five listening part
two now look at part
two for each question write the correct
answer in the Gap write one word or a
number or a date or a time look at
questions 6 to 10 now you have 10
seconds you will hear Damian telling his
friend about Anna's surprise
party hi it's Damian here sorry I didn't
see you yesterday I thought I should
ring and give you the information about
Anna's surprise party tomorrow it's at B
a restaurant I've booked the table
because it's always busy there weren't
any tables free at 7 or
7:30 so I've booked one for
8:15 so we'll eat a bit later do you
know where the restaurant is it's 62
Orchard Street that's o r c h a r d it's
a bit difficult to get there by bus but
you can take the train it's very close
to the city center
station I'll bring Anna I've invited her
to my house but she doesn't know
anything about the party and Susie will
bring the flowers for her but could you
take your camera to the restaurant
please it'll be nice to have some good
photos of the evening ring me if you're
not sure about anything my mobile number
is 0
341 I can't wait to see everyone
bye now listen
again hi it's Damian here sorry I didn't
see you yesterday I thought I should
ring and give you the information about
Anna's surprise party tomorrow it's at
Banana restaurant I've booked the table
because it's always busy there weren't
any tables free at 7 or
7:30 so I've booked one for 8:15 so
we'll eat a bit later do you know where
the restaurant is it's 62 Orchard Street
that's o r c h a r d it's a bit
difficult to get there by bus but you
can take the train it's very close to
the city center
station I'll bring Anna I've invited her
to my house but she doesn't know
anything about the party and Susie will
bring the flowers for her but could you
take your camera to the restaurant
please it'll be nice to have some good
photos of the evening ring me if you're
not sure about anything my mobile numers
341 I can't wait to see everyone
bye that is the end of part
two test five listening part
three now look at part
three for each question choose the
correct
answer look at questions 11 to 15 now
you have 20 seconds
you will hear Vivien talking to her
brother Andy about buying a new video
game hi Vivien hi Andy do you want some
of this pizza it's really nice no thanks
I've had lunch I've just come back from
the shops and I'm so hungry I bought
this new video game I can't wait to play
it another game didn't you buy Star
driver last week so this one's race week
is it like that new game winner no it's
different a college friend told me about
it he said it was on a TV show about
video games and it looked good after I
bought it I heard an advert for it on
the radio it's really popular did you
get it from top computers actually no I
I got it from small world it's not
cheaper but there's more variety and the
staff are really nice like the staff at
top computers have you been there yes
but I thought the shop was a bit dark it
was bigger than I thought there was lots
of space even on a busy Saturday and
they were playing really cool loud music
when I
went now listen again
hi Vivian hi Andy do you want some of
this pizza it's really nice no thanks
I've had lunch I've just come back from
the shops and I'm so hungry I bought
this new video game I can't wait to play
it another game didn't you buy Star
driver last week so this one's race week
is it like that new game winner no it's
different a college friend told me about
it
he said it was on a TV show about video
games and it looked good after I bought
it I heard an advert for it on the radio
it's really popular did you get it from
top computers actually no I got it from
small world it's not cheaper but there's
more variety and the staff are really
nice like the staff at top computers
have you been there yes but I thought
the shop was a bit dark it was bigger
than I thought there was lots of space
even on a busy Saturday and they were
playing really cool loud music when I
went that is the end of part
three test five listening part four
now look at part
four for each question choose the
correct answer look at questions 16 to
20 now you have 15 seconds
16 you will hear Jack leaving a message
for his friend what does Jack want his
friend to
do hi it's Jack bad news I didn't manage
to get tickets for the concert on
Saturday night there are still some
tickets available for Friday if Friday
is okay with you could you get two
tickets on your way home I can't get to
the ticket of office because I promised
to visit my sister after work
thanks now listen
again hi it's Jack bad news I didn't
manage to get tickets for the concert on
Saturday night there are still some
tickets available for Friday if Friday
is okay with you could you get two
tickets on your way home I can't get to
to the ticket office because I promised
to visit my sister after work
thanks
17 you will hear a girl Annabelle
talking about her
weekend what does Annabelle say about
cycling in the
mountains hi Annabelle where did you go
cycling at the weekend we planned to go
to the mountains but it was freezing
I hate cycling in the city it's too
dangerous so we ended up going to the
woods instead it was really beautiful
and there were special cycle paths it
was much easier than cycling in the
mountains now listen
again hi Annabelle where did you go
cycling at the weekend
we planned to go to the mountains but it
was
freezing I hate cycling in the city it's
too
dangerous so we ended up going to the
woods instead it was really beautiful
and there were special cycle paths it
was much easier than cycling in the
mountains 18 you will hear a basketball
coach talking to the basketball team why
must the team do extra practice before
the
match so it's the big match on Saturday
and I really think we can win it if we
put in some extra effort that's why I
want us to have some extra practice
tomorrow I want us to play the best we
possibly can on Saturday I don't want
any players to miss this extra practice
don't disappoint me
now listen
again so it's the big match on Saturday
and I really think we can win it if we
put in some extra effort that's why I
want us to have some extra practice
tomorrow I want us to play the best we
possibly can on Saturday I don't want
any players to miss this extra practice
don't disappoint
me 19 you will hear a boy Daniel talking
about a restaurant what does Daniel say
about the
restaurant have you been to Bernie's
Burgers yet yes I went last night I was
really hungry so I had the double
cheeseburger and large fries I
definitely wasn't hungry afterwards
but it wasn't the best burger I've ever
had but it's good if you just want
something big and cheap though and you
don't have much time I
agree now listen
again have you been to Bernie's Burgers
yet yes I went last night I was really
hungry so I had the double cheeseburger
and large fries
I definitely wasn't hungry afterwards
but it wasn't the best burger I've ever
had but it's good if you just want
something big and cheap though and you
don't have much time I
agree 20 you will hear a woman talking
to her neighbor about the weather what
was the weather like last
night morning
morning look at the mess in my garden
after the weather last night I've got
lots of tidying up to do there were
leaves everywhere yes it was terrible
and very noisy it woke me up me too at
least it was dry last night and it's
still quite warm yes I think it's
supposed to get colder
tomorrow now listen again
morning morning look at the mess in my
garden after the weather last night I've
got lots of tidying up to do there are
leaves everywhere yes it was terrible
and very noisy it woke me up me too at
least it was dry last night and it's
still quite warm yes I think it's
supposed to get colder tomorrow
that is the end of part
four test five listening part
five now look at part
five for each question choose the
correct answer look at questions 21 to
25 now you have 15
seconds you will hear Tim talking to a
friend about an activity holiday what
activity did Tim do on each
day hi Tim how was your activity holiday
it was fantastic what did you do well on
the first day Wednesday we went for a
long walk along the river sounds nice
yeah it was on Thursday we had to choose
between going horse riding and going
fishing most people wanted to go on a
horse so that's what we did I'd love to
do that what else did you do on Friday
we went to the lake and went for a swim
there were lots of small fish in the
water really yeah on Saturday afternoon
we wanted to play beach volleyball but
it started to rain so we stayed at the
activity center and played board games
it was actually really good fun what
about Sunday we planned to play tennis
but most of us still wanted to play
volleyball so we decided to do that what
did you do after that on the last day
Monday we went back to the lake this
time we did wind surfing instead of
swimming it was fun but quite difficult
sounds
great now listen
again hi Tim how was your activity
holiday it was fantastic what did you do
well on the first day Wednesday we went
for a long walk along the river sounds
nice yeah it was on Thursday we had to
choose between going horse riding and
going fishing most people wanted to go
on a horse so that's what we did I'd
love to do that what else did you do on
Friday we went to the lake and went for
a swim there were lots of small fish in
the water really yeah
on Saturday afternoon we wanted to play
beach volleyball but it started to rain
so we stayed at the activity center and
played board games it was actually
really good fun what about Sunday we
planned to play tennis but most of us
still wanted to play volleyball so we
decided to do that what did you do after
that on the last day Monday we went back
to the lake this time we did wind
surfing instead of swimming it was fun
but quite difficult sounds
great that is the end of part five you
now have 6 minutes to write your answers
on the answer
sheet
e
e e
you have one more
minute e
that is the end of the
test
e
e e