practice tests for A2 key copyright
Harper Collins Publishers
2020 key English test
listening there are five parts to the
test you will hear each piece
twice we will now stop for a
moment please ask any questions now
because you must not speak during the
test
now look at the instructions for part
one for each question choose the correct
answer look at question
one one how will David
travel hi
David what a lot of luggage where are
you going I'm going on holiday
are you going to the airport well we
wanted to fly but the flights were so
expensive H the train can be too but we
found discount train tickets online even
cheaper than the
coach have a good
trip now listen
again hi
David what a lot of luggage
where are you going I'm going on
holiday are you going to the airport
well we wanted to fly but the flights
were so
expensive H the train can be too but we
found discounts train tickets online
even cheaper than the
coach have a good
trip
two what time will Roger see the
dentist hello can I make an appointment
to see the dentist please let me see
there are times available next
Friday how about
1:00 I've got a working lunch then is
there anything later I can come after 3
I've got one available at 3: and one at
halfast 3
okay I'll take the later one
please now listen
again hello can I make an appointment to
see the dentist please let me see there
a times available next
Friday how about
1:00 I've got a working lunch then is
there anything later I can come after 3
I I've got one available at 3 and one at
halfast 3 okay I'll take the later one
please
three how much will Vera pay for her
lunch can I have my bill please you had
the chicken correct that's
750 and uh chocolate cake that's £3
isn't it
so that's
£150 today dessert is half price so
£750 plus
£150 oh so
nine here's A10 note I'll get your
change now listen
again can I have my bill please you had
the chicken correct that's
£750 and uh chocolate cake that's £3
isn't it so that's
£150 today dessert is half price so
£750 plus
£150 oh so
nine here's a £10 note I'll get your
change four
what will the friends do in the
afternoon would you like to play tennis
this afternoon maybe I was thinking of
going to the indoor swimming pool but
the weather's lovely what about the
beach but we can't play tennis on the
beach they say the weather will change
so let's go to the beach before it's too
late okay we'll keep tennis and the pool
for another
day now listen
again would you like to play tennis this
afternoon maybe I was thinking of going
to the indoor swimming pool but the
weather's lovely what about the beach
but we can't play tennis on the beach
they say the weather will change so
let's go to the beach before it's too
late okay we'll keep tennis and the pool
for another
day five what pet will Janet
have Janet wants a dog not in this house
a cat possibly or a fish oh she can't
play with a fish that's why she wants a
dog we can go on holiday and leave a
fish alone you can leave cats
too I see a cat fine I still think a
fish would be good just don't ask me to
look after the
cat now listen
again Janet wants a dog not in this
house a cat possibly or a fish oh she
can't play with a fish that's why she
want a dog we can go on holiday and
leave a fish alone you can leave cats
too I see a cat fine I still think a
fish would be good just don't ask me to
look after the
cat that is the end of part
one now look at part
two for each Quest question write the
correct answer in the Gap write one word
or a number or a date or a
time look at questions 6 to 10
now you have 10
seconds you will hear a woman talking to
a group of students about the
library welcome to the library you will
all come here a lot so there's some
important information that you need to
know first of all the hours the library
is
open during term time the library is
open 24 hours a day but outside term
time it's open from half 8 in the
morning until 7:00 in the
evening of course you will want to take
things out of the
library you can borrow different things
like magazines CDs books you can take up
to 10 different things out of the
library but only six books at one
time but please be careful if you return
things late you will have to pay a
fine the cost is £2 a day for each book
And1 a day for other
things library cards are free but you
need to fill in a form and give it in
with a photo if you lose your card you
can get a new one but it will
cost5 now listen
again welcome to the library you will
all come here a lot so there's some
important information that you need to
know first of all the hours the library
is
open during term time the library is
open 24 hours a day but outside term
time it's open from halfast 8 in the
morning until 7:00 in the
evening of course you will want to take
things out of the
library you can borrow different things
like magazines CDs books you can take up
to 10 different things out of the
library but only six books at one
time but please be careful if you return
things late you will have to pay a
fine the cost is 2 a day for each book
and one a day for other
things library cards are free but you
need to fill in a form and give it in
with a photo if you lose your card you
can get a new one but it will cost
5 that is the end of part
two now look at part
three for each question choose the
correct
answer look at questions 11 to 15 now
you have 20
seconds you will hear Jane talking to
her friend David about going to the
cinema hi David
have you got any plans for this evening
some of us are thinking of going to the
cinema hello Jane that sounds great what
are you going to see well we haven't
decided yet there's a new action film
out a James Bond film but Robert's
coming and he isn't a fan of action
films uh what else is on let me try and
remember what I saw on the
website there was a romantic film two
people fall in love but one of them gets
ill and dies young it sounds good but
really sad no I really don't enjoy films
like that at all are there any other
choices there's a comedy and people say
it's very funny and a cartoon for
children well what's about the funny one
Everyone likes a laugh don't they okay
yeah why not shall we pick you up on our
way there about 8 that's a
plan now listen
again hi David have you got any plans
for this evening some of us are thinking
of going to the cinema hello J
that sounds great what are you going to
see well we haven't decided yet there's
a new action film out a James Bond film
but Robert's coming and he isn't a fan
of action films uh what else is on let
me try and remember what I saw on the
website there was a romantic film two
people falling in love but one of them
gets ill and dies young it sounds good
but really sad no I really don't enjoy
films like that at all are there any
other choices there's a comedy and
people say it's very funny and a cartoon
for children well what about the funny
one Everyone likes a laugh don't they
okay yeah why not shall we pick you up
on our way there about 8 that's a
plan that is the end of part
three now look at part
four for each question choose the
correct
answer
16 you will hear a woman talking to her
friend about a meal at a restaurant
what did she
eat did you enjoy your meal last night M
it was delicious what did you have well
it was a steak restaurant but there were
other things on the menu too like fish
and pasta David told me he had the pasta
yes but then he spent the whole meal
looking at my fish
now listen
again did you enjoy your meal last
night it was
delicious what did you have well it was
a steak restaurant but there were other
things on the menu too like fish and
pasta David told me he had the pasta yes
but then he spent the whole meal looking
at my fish
17 you will hear a man explaining why he
was late for
work why was he
late I'm sorry for being late I couldn't
do anything about it I woke up earlier
than usual and got my train okay and the
train was on time today for a change but
the road from the station was blocked
with traffic so the bus took over and
hour usually it's a 10-minute Journey
the traffic lights weren't
working now listen
again I'm sorry for being late I
couldn't do anything about it I woke up
earlier than usual and got my train okay
and the train was on time today for a
change but the road from the station was
blocked with traffic so the bus took
over an hour usually it's a 10-minute
Journey the traffic lights weren't
working
18 you will hear two friends talking
about
holidays where did Anita
go did you have a nice holiday Anita
fantastic thanks you went to New York
didn't you we did not that it was
planned oh you see we had booked Florida
but we were offered a change at the last
moment because of the bad weather there
Los Angeles was also a possibility nice
to have a
choice now listen
again did you have a nice holiday Anita
fantastic thanks you went to New York
didn't you we did not that it was
planned oh you see we had booked Florida
but we were offered a change at the last
moment
because of the bad weather there Los
Angeles was also a possibility nice to
have a
choice
19 you will hear two friends talking
about
shopping what do they need from the
supermarket please get some potatoes
when you go out we've got some they're
in the cupboard with the other
vegetables oh oh uh but there aren't any
carrots because we never eat them we buy
them and then we throw them out but I
want to make carrot cake I haven't made
it for months
okay
onions we're okay for
onions now listen
again please get some potatoes when you
go out we've got some
they're in the cupboard with the other
vegetables oh uh but there aren't any
carrots because we never eat them we buy
them and then we throw them out but I
want to make carrot cake I haven't made
it for months
okay
onions we're okay for
onions
20 you will hear a m
talking on the
phone why can't he come to the
party I'm sorry I left work early so I
could come but it's my mother you met
her when she visited me didn't you she's
had a fall and I want to check that
she's all right I need to pay her a
visit anyway I was going to see her
tomorrow after work but but I think I
should go
now now listen
again I'm sorry I left work early so I
could come but it's my mother you met
her when she visited me didn't you she's
had a fall and I want to check that
she's all right I need to pay her a
visit anyway I was going to see her
tomorrow after work but I think I should
go
now that is the end of part
four now look at part five for each
question choose the correct
answer look at questions 21 to 25 now
you have 15 seconds
you will hear Greta talking to Anthony
about
holidays what type of holiday will each
person go
on hello Anthony are you getting ready
for your holiday yes Greta we're very
excited we've got new boots this year
and we're going to try and do about 16
kilom a day great I talked to Julie
earlier she's got her Sun cream and hat
ready it's Sun Sea and Sand for her
holiday this year yes and she said I
could use her tent my sister and I are
going to Scotland sleeping out in a
field that's not for me I hope the
weather is nice for you talking about
holidays you know John my neighbor yes
didn't he go skiing last winter yes and
he broke his leg he said never again
after
that he's booked a tour of four European
Capital Cities he showed me a long list
of interesting places he's going to
visit I thought he was going cycling
with Jenny that was the plan but not
anymore Jenny couldn't go she has to
work all summer she'll be home alone
then because Ed will be away on his
boat now listen
again hello Anthony are you getting
ready for your holiday yes Greta we're
very excited we've got new boots this
year and we're going to try and do about
16 kilm a day great I talked to J Julie
earlier she's got her Sun cream and hat
ready it's Sun Sea and Sand for her
holiday this year yes and she said I
could use her tent my sister and I are
going to Scotland sleeping out in the
field that's not for me I hope the
weather is nice for you talking about
holidays you know John my neighbor yes
didn't he go skiing last winter yes yes
and he broke his leg he said never again
after
that he's booked a tour of four European
Capital Cities he showed me a long list
of interesting places he's going to
visit I thought he was going cycling
with Jenny that was the plan but not
anymore Jenny couldn't go she has to
work or Sumer she'll be home alone then
because Ed will be away on his boat
that is the end of part five you now
have six minutes to write your answers
on the answer sheet