For each question, choose the correct
answer.
Look at question one.
One.
Where were the sunglasses
the last time Mark saw them?
>> Mark, have you seen my sunglasses?
>> You had them on Saturday at the beach.
They were in your backpack.
>> I've looked. They aren't there.
>> What about on your desk? You often put
things there.
>> Good idea. I'll look now.
>> Oh, and look on the bookcase, too.
Maybe you put them there with your keys.
Now listen again.
>> Mark, have you seen my sunglasses?
>> You had them on Saturday at the beach.
They were in your backpack.
>> I've looked. They aren't there.
>> What about on your desk? You often put
things there.
>> Good idea. I'll look now.
>> Oh, and look on the bookcase, too.
Maybe you put them there with your keys.
Two.
Where did the man see the ad for the
concert?
>> Hey, Sandy. Are you going to the concert
in the park this year?
>> Oh, I haven't heard anything about a
concert.
>> That's strange. Tina usually puts ads
about local events on the noticeboard.
>> I'd love to go. Where can we get
tickets?
>> The ad in the newspaper this morning
said we can get them online.
>> Great. I can't wait.
>> Now listen again.
Hey, Sandy. Are you going to the concert
in the park this year?
>> Oh, I haven't heard anything about a
concert.
>> That's strange.
Tina usually puts ads about local events
on the notice board.
>> I'd love to go.
Where can we get tickets?
>> The ad in the newspaper this morning
said we can get them online.
>> Great. I can't wait.
>> Three.
Who is Simon?
>> Thanks for coming to the party, David.
>> It's nice to be here.
>> Come and meet my brother, Simon. He's
over there.
>> Is he the guy with the dark hair and the
blue jacket?
>> No, that's my cousin, Max. My brother is
the one with the dark hair and shirt
talking to the tall man with the
glasses.
>> I'll go and say hi.
>> Now listen again.
>> Thanks for coming to the party, David.
>> It's nice to be here.
>> Come and meet my brother, Simon. He's
over there.
>> Is he the guy with the dark hair and the
blue jacket?
>> No, that's my cousin, Max. My brother is
the one with the dark hair and shirt
talking to the tall man with the
glasses.
>> I'll go and say hi.
>> Four.
What job does the woman want help with?
>> Tanya,
do you need any help? I can wash the
dirty dishes for you.
>> Don't worry. I've already put them in
the dishwasher.
>> How about if I cut up those vegetables
next to the cooker?
>> Ah, great. That would be a big help.
Thank you. And the kids can put away the
dishes when come out of the dishwasher.
>> Now listen again.
Tanya, do you need any help? I can wash
the dirty dishes for you.
>> Don't worry. I've already put them in
the dishwasher.
>> How about if I cut up those vegetables
next to the cooker?
>> Ah, great. That would be a big help.
Thank you. And the kids can put away the
dishes when they come out of the
dishwasher.
>> Five.
When might the next bus arrive?
>> Excuse me.
What time is the next bus?
>> It usually comes at 25 past 3:00.
But the buses are running about 20
minutes late today.
>> Really?
So, it will be here at quarter to four.
I need to be at the dentist at four.
>> Maybe you should take a taxi.
>> I will.
It takes about half an hour to get to
the dentist by bus.
>> Now listen again.
>> Excuse me.
What time is the next bus?
>> It usually comes at 25 past 3:00.
But the buses are running about 20
minutes late today.
>> Really?
So, it will be here at quarter to four.
I need to be at the dentist at four.
>> Maybe you should take a taxi.
>> I will.
It takes about half an hour to get to
the dentist by bus.
>> That is the end of part one.
Now look at part two.
For each question, write the correct
answer in the gap.
Write one word or a number or a date or
a time.
Look at questions 6 to 10 now.
You have 10 seconds.
You will hear a tour guide talking about
a boat tour in Venice.
>> Welcome aboard.
Before we begin our tour, let me tell
you a few things about this beautiful
city.
Venice is built on a number of islands
in the Adriatic Sea.
No one knows the exact number,
but we think there are 118.
Between the islands, there are 150
canals.
Today, we are going to travel along the
Grand Canal, the city's busiest canal.
It's also the longest,
almost 4 km long.
You won't see any cars, of course, but
there will be lots of different boats.
We will pass under four bridges,
but there are many more in the city.
Venice has 391
bridges,
and most of them are very beautiful.
You should try and see some of them
while you're here.
Our boat trip today will take about 30
minutes.
We will go past many the city's famous
churches, museums, and palaces.
We will even go past the fish market.
Now,
please be seated, and we will begin our
tour right here on the
>> Now listen again.
>> Welcome aboard.
Before we begin our tour, let me tell
you a few things about this beautiful
city.
Venice is built on a number of islands
in the Adriatic Sea.
No one knows the exact number,
but we think there are 118.
Between the islands, there are 150
canals.
Today, we're going to travel along the
Grand Canal, the city's busiest canal.
It's also the longest,
almost 4 km long.
You won't see any cars, of course, but
there will be lots of different boats.
We will pass under four bridges, but
there are many more in the city.
Venice has 391
bridges, and most of them are very
beautiful.
You should try and see some of them
while you're here.
Our boat trip today will take about 30
minutes.
We will go past many of the city's
famous churches, museums, and palaces.
We will even go past the fish market.
Now,
please be seated, and we will begin our
tour right here on the
>> That is the end of part two.
Now look at part three.
For each question, choose the correct
answer.
Look at questions 11 to 15 now.
You have 20 seconds.
You will hear Lisa talking to her friend
Robin about finding a place to live.
>> Where are you going to live while you're
at university, Lisa?
>> I'm not sure.
>> It isn't easy, is it, Robin?
A secretary I spoke to told me about
some university flats, but I'd also like
to look online and visit some other
places.
>> What does the university offer?
>> There are 20 flats in an apartment
building in the city center. Four
students share a flat,
but I'm not sure about it.
It's 9 km from the university.
And what if I don't like the other
students in the flat?
>> Mhm.
What else is there?
>> Two buildings near the university.
Howard House and Morgan House.
Howard House is more expensive, but
there's a canteen, and the price
includes meals.
Morgan House is cheaper, but you only
pay for your room.
>> So, there's no canteen in Morgan House?
>> That's right.
But on each floor, there's a kitchen and
four bathrooms.
Oh, and there are 25 students on each
floor.
>> Oh.
So, which one do you think is better?
Howard House or Morgan House?
>> Well, they sound good, but I want to see
them and meet the students who live
there.
>> Right. Because what do you do if you
don't like them?
>> Mhm, that could be a problem.
>> Now, listen again.
Where are you going to live while you're
at university, Lisa?
I'm not sure.
>> It isn't easy, is it, Robin?
A secretary I spoke to told me about
some university flats,
but I'd also like to look online and
visit some other places.
>> What does the university offer?
>> There are 20 flats in an apartment
building in the city center. Four
students share a flat,
but I'm not sure about it.
It's 9 km from the university.
And what if I don't like the other
students in the flat?
>> Mhm.
What else is there?
>> Two buildings near the university.
Howard House and Morgan House.
Howard House is more expensive, but
there's a canteen and the price includes
meals.
Morgan House is cheaper, but you only
pay for your room.
>> So, there's no canteen in Morgan House.
>> That's right.
But, on each floor, there's a kitchen
and four bathrooms.
Oh, and there are 25 students on each
floor.
>> Oh.
So, which one do you think is better?
Howard House or Morgan House?
>> Well, they sound good, but I want to see
them and meet the students who live
there.
>> Right. Because what do you do if you
don't like them?
>> Mhm, that could be a problem.
>> That is the end of part three.
Now look at part four.
For each question, choose the correct
answer.
You will hear two friends talking about
the weather.
What is the weather going to be like
tomorrow?
>> Do you think it will be warmer tomorrow?
I'm so tired of all this rain.
>> Yes, I know. I can't wait until summer.
It doesn't look sunny on the weather
app.
And the wind will be quite strong.
And it's going to be rainy again at the
weekend.
>> Oh, well. At least it won't be wet
tomorrow.
>> Now listen again.
>> Do you think it will be warmer tomorrow?
I'm so tired of all this rain.
>> Yes, I know. I can't wait until summer.
It doesn't look sunny on the weather
app. And the wind will be quite strong.
And it's going to be rainy again at the
weekend.
>> Oh, well. At least it won't be wet
tomorrow.
>> 17
You will hear a man talking to a friend
on the phone.
Why is he angry?
>> You won't believe it. You know the suit
I wore to the meeting last week? I took
it to the dry cleaners and they said
they could clean it in an hour.
So, I went to a cafe to wait.
When I returned, I paid and came home.
But, when I looked carefully at the
suit, it was still dirty.
I paid a lot of money for nothing.
>> Now, listen again.
>> You won't believe it. You know the suit
I wore to the meeting last week? I took
it to the dry cleaners and they said
they could clean it in an hour.
So, I went to a cafe to wait.
When I returned, I paid and came home.
But, when I looked carefully at the
suit, it was still dirty.
I paid a lot of money for nothing.
>> 18.
You will hear a woman talking to her
friend about work.
Why is she unhappy?
>> Do you have any holidays planned,
Michelle?
>> No, unfortunately.
I have to work on Saturday and Sunday
twice this month. And I'm not pleased
about that.
>> So, how many hours a week are you
working now?
>> About 20 hours.
But, I also work a couple of evenings in
the week.
>> Now, listen again.
Do you have any holidays planned,
Michelle?
>> No, unfortunately.
I have to work on Saturday and Sunday
twice this month. And I'm not pleased
about that.
>> So, how many hours a week are you
working now?
>> About 20 hours.
But, I also work a couple of evenings in
the week.
>> 19.
You will hear a man talking to his
friend about where he lives.
What does he say about it?
>> Where do you live now, Chris?
>> On the other side of town. I share a
house with two other people.
>> Do you like it there?
>> Yes and no. I need 30 minutes to cycle
here in the morning. The traffic is
terrible.
>> So, why did you move far from work?
>> The city center was too noisy for me.
Now listen again.
>> Where do you live now, Chris?
>> On the other side of town. I share a
house with two other people.
>> Do you like it there?
>> Yes and no. I need 30 minutes to cycle
here in the morning. The traffic is
terrible.
>> So, why did you move far from work?
>> The city center was too noisy for me.
You will hear two friends talking about
a sports center.
Which sport is the woman going to do?
>> So, are you going to become a member of
the sports center?
>> Yes. Actually, I joined last week. I was
quite good at football at school and I'd
love to play with the local team here,
but maybe I'll try another ball game,
too.
>> How about volleyball or tennis?
>> Mhm, I've never tried them, but I'll
think about it.
Now listen again.
So, are you going to become a member of
the sports center? Yes. Actually, I
joined last week. I was quite good at
football at school and I'd love to play
with the local team here, but maybe I'll
try another ball game, too.
>> How about volleyball or tennis?
>> Mhm. I've never tried them, but I'll
think about it.
>> That is the end of part four.
Now look at part five.
For each question, choose the correct
answer.
Look at questions 21 to 25 now.
You have 15 seconds.
You will hear Charlie talking to his
friend Evie about visiting his family.
What gift did he buy for each person?
>> When are you going home, Charlie?
>> Tomorrow. And I've bought everyone a
gift. Look.
>> Mhm.
Who are these for?
>> Ah, Granny.
Her hands get cold in the winter and
these will keep them nice and warm.
>> Is the scarf for her, too?
>> No, that's for Granddad.
I also got him this.
He needs a new one. He lost his wallet
last month.
>> Nice.
What did you get your mom?
>> Oh, I bought her these earrings
and this bracelet.
>> Oh, Charlie, they're beautiful.
>> Huh,
they're a special gift because it's her
birthday tomorrow.
>> What What your dad?
>> Oh, I got him this.
Everyone else in my family listens to
music on their phones, but not dad.
He'll also enjoy listening to the news
on it in the mornings.
>> Mhm.
And your brother?
>> Oh, he's football mad.
I was going to get him a football shirt,
but then I saw this.
It's a history of his team, and there
are some great photos in it.
>> What about your sister?
>> This.
It's bigger than her school bag, and she
can put all her books and lots of things
in it.
>> Oh, I love the colors.
>> Now listen again.
>> When are you going home, Charlie?
>> Tomorrow, and I've bought everyone a
gift. Look.
>> Mhm.
Who are these for?
>> Oh, granny.
Her hands get cold in the winter, and
these will keep them nice and warm.
>> Is the scarf for her, too?
>> No, that's for granddad.
I also got him this.
He needs a new one. He lost his wallet
last month.
>> Nice.
What did you get your mom?
>> Oh,
I bought her these earrings
and this bracelet.
>> Oh, Charlie, they're beautiful.
>> They're a special gift because it's her
birthday tomorrow.
>> What about your dad?
>> Oh, I got him this.
Everyone else in my family listens to
music on their phones, but not dad.
He'll also enjoy listening to the news
on it in the mornings.
>> Mhm.
And your brother?
>> Oh, he's football mad.
I I going to get him a football shirt,
but then I saw this.
It's a history of his team and there are
some great photos in it.
>> What about your sister?
>> This.
It's bigger than her school bag and she
can put all her books and lots of things
in it.
>> Oh, I love the colors.
>> That is the end of part