for each question choose the correct
answer
one how did Richard travel from the
airport Richard what are you doing here
I was planning to pick you up from the
airport at 3: oh I arrived at 2 I told
you the wrong time to meet me so sorry
but a taxi from the airport so
expensive did you take the bus my
colleague Andy gave me a lift that's why
I'm home so
early now listen
again Richard what are you doing here I
was planning to pick you up from the
airport at 3:00 oh I arrived at 2 I told
you the wrong time to meet me sorry but
a taxi from the airport so
expensive did you take the bus my
colleague Andy gave me a lift that's why
I'm home so
early
two what is next to the woman's new
flat do you like your new flat Amanda
very much thanks my old one was next to
a railway station so it was a bit noisy
but your new building beside the river
is very different isn't it yes it takes
10 minutes to walk to the nearest shop
but I don't mind that
great now listen
again do you like your new flat Amanda
very much thanks my old one was next to
a railway station so it was a bit noisy
but your new building beside the river
is very different isn't it yes it takes
10 minutes to walk to the nearest shop
but I don't mind that
great
three what job does the man
do you look tired Paul has work been
busy yes very several cars were stolen
in this area this week so we've had a
lot of extra work to do fortunately we
found them a garage is checking them but
they seem okay so now can you have a
rest yes I'm going to spend all weekend
at home playing the piano
now listen
again you look tired Paul has work been
busy yes very several cars were stolen
in this area this week so we've had a
lot of extra work to do fortunately we
found them a garage is checking them but
they seem okay so now can you have a
rest yes I'm going to spend all weekend
at home playing the
piano
four which t-shirt does the girl decide
to
buy why don't you get your little
brother this t-shirt Daisy I like the
stars on it yes but that one with a
lion's head is very
unusual and I love this one too with a
drum on it so which one would he prefer
do you think probably the one you found
I'll get that
one now listen
again why don't you get your little
brother this t-shirt Daisy I like the
stars on it yes but that one with a
lion's head is very
unusual and I love this one too with a
drum on it so which one would he prefer
do you think probably the one you found
I'll get that
one
five where are the car
keys Lisa I can't find my car keys have
you seen them have you looked on the
bookcase you sometimes leave them on top
of it yeah yes but they aren't there I
left them on the kitchen table but I
can't see them now here they are in this
drawer in the kitchen I probably put
them there when I was tidying up
thanks now listen
again Lisa I can't find my car keys have
you seen them have you looked on the
bookcase you sometimes leave them on on
top of it yes but they aren't there I
left them on the kitchen table but I
can't see them now here they are in this
drawer in the kitchen I probably put
them there when I was tidying up
thanks that is the end of part one
now look at part
two for each question write the correct
answer in the
Gap write one word or a number or a date
or a
time look at question six to 10
now you have 10 seconds
you will hear someone talking on the
radio about a
competition I want to tell you about a
very exciting short story competition
it's for 16year olds so if you are one
or no one listen carefully there are
some brilliant prizes three stories will
win a camera but the best story will win
a computer a fantastic prize I'm sure
you'll agree there are some special
things to say about the story it must be
750 words exactly 800 is too many and
700 is too few it can be a funny story
or a happy story but there's one one
word you have to use and that's snow so
your story could take place in winter or
in the mountains perhaps you must send
your story To Us by the 19th of June
it's the 3rd of June now so you have two
weeks to get the perfect story ready
upload your story to our website it's
www.car.com I'll spell that for you c a
r o w you can see all the details of the
competition there
too now listen
again I want to tell you about a very
exciting short story competition it's
for 16-year-olds so if you are one or no
one listen carefully there are some
brilliant prizes three stories will win
a camera but the best story will win a
computer a fantastic prize I'm sure
you'll agree there are some special
things to say about the story it must be
750 words exactly 800 is too many and
700 is too few it can be a funny story
or a happy story but there's one word
you have to use and that's snow so your
story could take place in winter or in
the mountains perhaps you must send your
story To Us by the 19th of June it's the
3rd of June now so you have two weeks to
get the perfect story ready upload your
story to our website it's www.car.com
I'll spell that for you c a r o w you
can see all the details of the
competition there
too that is the end of part
two now look at part
three for each question choose the
correct
answer look at questions 11 to 15
now you have 20 seconds
you will hear a brother and sister Ben
and Lily talking about their mother's
birthday hi Ben don't forget it's Mom's
birthday next week let's buy her present
tomorrow are you free after breakfast
I've got football practice Lily
and you've got a swimming lesson at 3:00
the shops are open until 9: shall we go
about 7:00 I can meet you in town
perfect let's get some earrings there's
a good jewelry shop in town it's
expensive can we look in the department
store okay there are some nice things
there they sell jewelry on the market
too but they're old things
yes are we going to have a party for Mom
I know how about taking her out for
lunch or have a barbecue in the park it
might rain let's go to a restaurant okay
shall we invite mom's best friend I
haven't seen her for a long time but I
think she'll come I'll ring her mom will
be excited great will you make your
special drink for m mom the lemon and
orange one actually I'm making something
better oh the melon and honey drink no
banana and cream
fantastic now listen
again hi Ben don't forget it's Mom's
birthday next week let's buy her present
tomorrow are you free after breakfast
I've got football practice Lily and
you've got a swimming lesson at 3:00 the
shops are open until 9: shall we go
about 7:00 I can meet you in town
perfect let's get some earrings there's
a good jewelry shop in town it's
expensive can we look in the department
store okay there are some nice things
there they sell Je on the market too but
they're old things yes are we going to
have a party for Mom I know how about
taking her out for lunch or have a
barbecue in the park it might rain let's
go to a restaurant okay shall we invite
mom's best friend I haven't seen her for
a long time but I think she'll come I'll
ring her mom will be excited great great
will you make your special drink for Mom
the lemon and orange one actually I'm
making something better oh the melon and
honey drink no banana and cream
fantastic that is the end of part three
now look at part
four for each question choose the
correct
answer
16 you will hear a woman telling her
friend about a
holiday what was the only only thing she
liked about her
holiday how was your trip not bad I only
booked an inexpensive room so I was
really worried it wasn't going to be
very nice but it was perfect and did you
go
sightseeing yeah I went on a walking
tour actually the guide wasn't great and
he recommended a terrible rest
restaurant for me to go to oh
dear now listen
again how is your trip not bad I only
booked an inexpensive room so I was
really worried it wasn't going to be
very nice but it was perfect and did you
go
sightseeing yeah I went on a walking
tour actually the guide wasn't great and
he recommended a terrible restaurant for
me to go to oh
dear
17 you will hear a woman talking to her
husband about a
problem why is the woman
upset what's the matter the mechanic
just called with some disappointing news
is it the engine yes it's going to cost
quite a lot and we don't really have the
money at the moment it's going to take a
while too well you can take my bike for
a few days I'll get the bus to
work now listen
again what's the matter the mechanic
just called with some disappointing news
is it the engine yes it's going to cost
quite a lot and we don't really have the
money at the moment it's going to take a
while too well you can take my bike for
a few days I'll get the bus to
work
18 you will hear an advertisement on the
radio what's the main reason for the
advertisement did you know that
Sportsworld is your newest sports shop
and we're opening this Friday with two
Champions playing table tennis for our
customers don't miss this exciting match
you should come and see our wide range
of sports kit with the best prices in
town we've got hundreds of items on our
shelves for everything from badminton to
wind
surfing now listen
again did you know that Sportsworld is
your newest sports shop and we're
opening this Friday with two Champions
playing table tennis for our customers
don't miss this EX exciting match you
should come and see our wide range of
sports kit with the best prices in town
we've got hundreds of items on our
shelves for everything from badminton to
wind
surfing
19 you will hear a boy talking with his
mother about one of his paintings
what doesn't the boy like about his
painting the bright colors you've used
for those Roses you've painted are
fantastic thanks Mom I spent hours
planning the way I wanted them to look
so I'm glad you've noticed that but
don't you think the painting's a bit too
large but it'll fit nicely above your
desk oh okay at least I now know how to
paint
flowers now listen
again the bright colors you've used for
those Roses you've painted are fantastic
thanks Mom I spent hours planning the
way I wanted them to look so I'm glad
you've noticed that but don't you think
the painting's a bit too large but it'll
fit nicely above your desk oh okay okay
at least I now know how to paint
flowers
20 you will hear a girl talking to her
father about a sports
blog what reason does the girl give for
liking the
blog dad you won't believe this I've won
a t-shirt from a sports blog oh really
how did you win that the Blogger asked
her readers to post their opinions about
her blog and she liked mine best what
did you say I thanked her for including
articles about famous
snowboarders that's why I read the blog
whenever I
can now listen
again Dad you won't believe this I've
won a t-shirt from a sports blog oh
really how did you win that the Blogger
asked her readers to post their opinions
about her blog and she liked mine best
what did you say I thanked her for
including articles about famous
snowboarders that's why I read the blog
whenever I can
that is the end of part
four now look at part
five for each question choose the
correct
answer look at questions 21 to 25
now you have 15
seconds you will hear a woman talking to
her teenage son about putting some
things in the right places in their new
house
where should her son put each
thing where shall I put this car
magazine mom leave it on the stairs
please I'll take it to my bedroom later
okay and does this bowl go in the
kitchen actually can you put it on the
shelf above the bath please
sure can I have this new lamp in my
bedroom sorry
it's for us to use
Outdoors so put it next to the apple
tree what's in this heavy box books some
of them will go in the living room and
some in my
bedroom put the box on the table next to
the cooker I'll move it before we need
the table for dinner
okay this clock was in the hall in our
old house wasn't it yes but I want it
next to my
wardrobe I like to know what time it is
when I wake up what about this chair
shall I put it in the living
room leave it in the entrance by the
front door it's very heavy so let's keep
it
downstairs now listen
again where shall I put this car
magazine mom
leave it on the stairs please I'll take
it to my bedroom later okay and does
this bowl go in the kitchen actually can
you put it on the shelf above the bath
please
sure can I have this new lamp in my
bedroom sorry it's for us to use
Outdoors so put it next to the apple
tree what's in this heavy box box books
some of them will go in the living room
and some in my
bedroom put the box on the table next to
the cooker I'll move it before we need
the table for dinner
okay this clock was in the hall in our
old house wasn't it yes but I want it
next to my
wardrobe I like to know what time it is
when I wake up what about this chair
shall I put it in the living
room leave it in the entrance by the
front door it's very heavy so let's keep
it
downstairs that is the end of part
five you now have 6 minutes to write
your answers on the answer
sheet
e
e e
you have one more
minute e