Listening part
one. There are five parts to the test.
You will hear each piece twice. Now look
at the instructions for part
one. For each question, choose the
correct
answer. Look at question one.
one. How much will the woman pay for the
laptop?
Can I help you? Uh, yes. Uh, I'd like to
buy a laptop for my son. I'd like to pay
about £600.
This one's on sale at the moment. From
£750, it's now down to £650. That's a
good discount from £750.
I'll take it. Fine.
Now, listen again.
Can I help you? Uh, yes. Uh, I'd like to
buy a laptop for my son. I'd like to pay
about £600.
This one's on sale at the moment. From
£750, it's now down to 650. That's a
good discount from
£750. I'll take it. Fine.
Two. What's Sue doing now?
Hi Sue. What are you doing? I was
studying, but I've just finished at the
moment. I'm watching my favorite nature
program. What about you? I'm doing my
college work. Do you want to go for a
walk later? Yes, I'd love to go for a
walk. Great. I'll come to your house at
7.
Now, listen again.
Hi, Sue. What are you doing? I was
studying, but I've just finished at the
moment. I'm watching my favorite nature
program. What about you? I'm doing my
college work. Do you want to go for a
walk later? Yes, I'd love to go for a
walk. Great. I'll come to your house at
7.
Three. What has Tom just finished doing?
Hi, Tom. Have you phoned our new
customer in Spain? He's really nice. Hi,
Rachel. I'm going to do that next. I've
just come out of a meeting with my
manager. Oh, what was that about? We
were talking about that email that I got
about maybe advertising on TV. Oh,
that's interesting.
Now, listen again.
Hi, Tom. Have you phoned our new
customer in Spain? He's really nice. Hi,
Rachel. I'm going to do that next. I've
just come out of a meeting with my
manager. Oh, what was that about? We
were talking about that email that I got
about maybe advertising on TV. Oh,
that's interesting.
Four. Who is Dan meeting at the weekend?
What are you doing at the weekend, Dan?
I'm meeting my friends, Rob and Sarah.
Is Sarah your friend with long fair
hair? That's Rosa. Sarah's got dark hair
and she wears glasses and robs her
younger brother, but he's taller than
her. He's still at school. He's got
short dark hair and glasses. Ah, yes. I
remember now.
Now listen again.
What are you doing at the weekend, Dan?
I'm meeting my friends Rob and Sarah. Is
Sarah your friend with long fair hair?
That's Rosa. Sarah's got dark hair and
she wears glasses and robs her younger
brother, but he's taller than her. He's
still at school. He's got short dark
hair and glasses. Ah, yes, I remember
now.
Five. What present is the boy going to
give Tina?
What are you going to buy Tina for her
birthday? I thought about perfume, but
I'm not sure which one she likes. Her
favorite writer has just written a new
horror story, so I'll get her that. Good
idea. I've bought her some earrings.
More jewelry. Doesn't she have enough
earrings? No.
Now listen again.
What are you going to buy Tina for her
birthday? I thought about perfume, but
I'm not sure which one she likes. Her
favorite writer has just written a new
horror story, so I'll get her that. Good
idea. I've bought her some earrings.
more jewelry. Doesn't she have enough
earrings? No.
That is the end of part
one. Test five, listening part
two. Now look at part two.
For each question, write the correct
answer in the gap. Write one word or a
number or a date or a
time. Look at questions 6 to 10. Now you
have 10 seconds.
You will hear Damian telling his friend
about Anna's surprise
party. Hi, it's Damian here. Sorry I
didn't see you yesterday. I thought I
should ring and give you the information
about Anna's surprise party tomorrow.
It's at Banana Restaurant. I booked the
table because it's always busy. There
weren't any tables free at 7 or 7:30, so
I've booked one for 8:15, so we'll eat a
bit later. Do you know where the
restaurant is? It's 62 Orchard Street.
That's O R C H A R D. It's a bit
difficult to get there by bus, but you
can take the train. It's very close to
the city center
station. I'll bring Anna. I've invited
her to my house, but she doesn't know
anything about the party. And Susie will
bring the flowers for her. But could you
take your camera to the restaurant,
please? It'll be nice to have some good
photos of the evening. Ring me if you're
not sure about anything. My mobile
number is
076456 341. I can't wait to see
everyone. Bye.
Now listen
again. Hi, it's Damian here. Sorry I
didn't see you yesterday. I thought I
should ring and give you the information
about Anna's surprise party tomorrow.
It's at Banana Restaurant. I've booked a
table because it's always busy. There
weren't any tables free at 7 or 7:30, so
I've booked one for 8:15. So, we'll eat
a bit later. Do you know where the
restaurant is? It's 62 Orchard Street.
That's O R C H A R D. It's a bit
difficult to get there by bus, but you
can take the train. It's very close to
the city center
station. I'll bring Anna. I've invited
her to my house, but she doesn't know
anything about the party. And Susie will
bring the flowers for her. But could you
take your camera to the restaurant,
please? It'll be nice to have some good
photos of the evening. Ring me if you're
not sure about anything. My mobile
number's
076456 341. I can't wait to see
everyone. Bye.
That is the end of part
two. Test five listening part
three. Now look at part three.
For each question, choose the correct
answer. Look at questions 11 to 15. Now
you have 20 seconds.
You will hear Vivian talking to her
brother Andy about buying a new video
game.
Hi Vivian. Hi Andy. Do you want some of
this pizza? It's really nice. No thanks.
I've had lunch. I've just come back from
the shops and I'm so hungry. I bought
this new video game. I can't wait to
play it. Another game. Didn't you buy
Star Driver last week? So, this one's
race week. Is it like that new game
Winner? No, it's different. A college
friend told me about it. He said it was
on a TV show about video games and it
looked good. After I bought it, I heard
an advert for it on the radio. It's
really popular. Did you get it from Top
Computers? Actually, no. I got it from
Small World. It's not cheaper, but
there's more variety. And the staff are
really nice, like the staff at Top
Computers. Have you been there? Yes, but
I thought the shop was a bit dark. It
was bigger than I thought. There was
lots of space, even on a busy Saturday,
and they were playing really cool, loud
music when I
went. Now listen again.
Hi, Vivian. Hi, Andy. Do you want some
of this pizza? It's really nice. No
thanks. I've had lunch. I've just come
back from the shops and I'm so hungry. I
bought this new video game. I can't wait
to play it. Another game. Didn't you buy
Star Driver last week? So, this one's
Race Week. Is it like that new game
Winner? No, it's different. A college
friend told me about it. He said it was
on a TV show about video games and it
looked good. After I bought it, I heard
an advert for it on the radio. It's
really popular. Did you get it from Top
Computers? Actually, no. I got it from
Small World. It's not cheaper, but
there's more variety, and the staff are
really nice, like the staff at Top
Computers. Have you been there? Yes, but
I thought the shop was a bit dark. It
was bigger than I thought. There was
lots of space even on a busy Saturday.
And they were playing really cool, loud
music when I
went. That is the end of part
three. Test five, listening part
four. Now look at part
four. For each question, choose the
correct answer. Look at questions 16 to
20. Now you have 15 seconds.
16. You will hear Jack leaving a message
for his friend. What does Jack want his
friend to do?
Hi, it's Jack. Bad news. I didn't manage
to get tickets for the concert on
Saturday night. There are still some
tickets available for Friday. If Friday
is okay with you, could you get two
tickets on your way home? I can't get to
the ticket office because I promise to
visit my sister after work. Thanks.
Now listen
again. Hi, it's Jack. Bad news. I didn't
manage to get tickets for the concert on
Saturday night. There are still some
tickets available for Friday. If Friday
is okay with you, could you get two
tickets on your way home? I can't get to
the ticket office because I promise to
visit my sister after work.
Thanks.
17. You will hear a girl, Annabelle,
talking about her weekend.
What does Annabelle say about cycling in
the mountains?
Hi, Annabelle. Where did you go cycling
at the weekend? We planned to go to the
mountains, but it was freezing. I hate
cycling in the city. It's too
dangerous. So, we ended up going to the
woods instead. It was really beautiful,
and there were special cycle paths. It
was much easier than cycling in the
mountains.
Now listen again.
Hi Annabelle. Where did you go cycling
at the weekend? We planned to go to the
mountains, but it was freezing. I hate
cycling in the city. It's too
dangerous. So we ended up going to the
woods instead. It was really beautiful
and there were special cycle paths. It
was much easier than cycling in the
mountains.
18. You will hear a basketball coach
talking to the basketball team. Why must
the team do extra practice before the
match?
So, it's the big match on Saturday, and
I really think we can win it if we put
in some extra effort. That's why I want
us to have some extra practice tomorrow.
I want us to play the best we possibly
can on Saturday. I don't want any
players to miss this extra practice.
Don't disappoint
me. Now, listen again.
So, it's the big match on Saturday, and
I really think we can win it if we put
in some extra effort. That's why I want
us to have some extra practice tomorrow.
I want us to play the best we possibly
can on Saturday. I don't want any
players to miss this extra practice.
Don't disappoint me.
19. You will hear a boy, Daniel, talking
about a restaurant. What does Daniel say
about the restaurant?
Have you been to Bernie's Burgers yet?
Yes, I went last night. I was really
hungry, so I had the double cheeseburger
and large fries. I definitely wasn't
hungry afterwards, but it wasn't the
best burger I've ever had. But it's good
if you just want something big and
cheap, though, and you don't have much
time. I agree.
Now, listen again.
Have you been to Bernie's Burgers yet?
Yes, I went last night. I was really
hungry, so I had the double cheeseburger
and large fries. I definitely wasn't
hungry afterwards, but it wasn't the
best burger I've ever had. But it's good
if you just want something big and
cheap, though, and you don't have much
time. I agree.
20. You will hear a woman talking to her
neighbor about the weather.
What was the weather like last night?
Morning. Morning. Look at the mess in my
garden after the weather last night.
I've got lots of tidying up to do. There
were leaves everywhere. Yes, it was
terrible and very noisy. It woke me up.
Me, too. At least it was dry last night
and it's still quite warm. Yes. I think
it's supposed to get colder tomorrow.
Now listen again.
Morning. Morning. Look at the mess in my
garden after the weather last night.
I've got lots of tidying up to do. There
were leaves everywhere. Yes, it was
terrible and very noisy. It woke me up.
Me, too. At least it was dry last night.
And it's still quite warm.
Yes, I think it's supposed to get colder
tomorrow. That is the end of part
four. Test five, listening part five.
Now look at part
five. For each question, choose the
correct answer. Look at questions 21 to
25. Now you have 15 seconds.
You will hear Tim talking to a friend
about an activity holiday. What activity
did Tim do on each day?
Hi Tim. How was your activity holiday?
It was fantastic. What did you do? Well,
on the first day, Wednesday, we went for
a long walk along the river. Sounds
nice. Yeah, it was. On Thursday, we had
to choose between going horse riding and
going fishing. Most people wanted to go
on a horse, so that's what we did. I'd
love to do that. What else did you do?
On Friday, we went to the lake and went
for a swim. There were lots of small
fish in the water. Really? Yeah. On
Saturday afternoon, we wanted to play
beach volleyball, but it started to
rain, so we stayed at the activity
center and played board games. It was
actually really good fun. What about
Sunday? We planned to play tennis, but
most of us still wanted to play
volleyball, so we decided to do that.
What did you do after that? On the last
day, Monday, we went back to the lake.
This time, we did wind surfing instead
of swimming. It was fun but quite
difficult. Sounds great.
Now listen again.
Hi Tim. How was your activity holiday?
It was fantastic. What did you do? Well,
on the first day, Wednesday, we went for
a long walk along the river. Sounds
nice. Yeah, it was. On Thursday, we had
to choose between going horse riding and
going fishing. Most people wanted to go
on a horse, so that's what we did. I'd
love to do that. What else did you do?
On Friday, we went to the lake and went
for a swim. There were lots of small
fish in the water. Really? Yeah. On
Saturday afternoon, we wanted to play
beach volleyball, but it started to
rain, so we stayed at the activity
center and played board games. It was
actually really good fun. What about
Sunday? We planned to play tennis, but
most of us still wanted to play
volleyball, so we decided to do that.
What did you do after that? On the last
day, Monday, we went back to the lake.
This time, we did wind surfing instead
of swimming. It was fun but quite
difficult. Sounds great.