Listening part
one. There are five parts to the test.
You will hear each piece twice. Now look
at the instructions for part
one. For each question, choose the
correct
answer. Look at question one.
One. What is Zach doing at the moment?
Do you know where Zach is, Sara? I
wanted to talk to him. Has he gone to
hockey practice? Hockey practice is
tomorrow, Dad. Maybe he's gone swimming.
But the pool's closed this week. Oh, I
didn't know that. Perhaps he's gone to
the park to play tennis. Oh, he's taken
his racket. That's where he is, then.
Now listen again.
Do you know where Zach is, Sara? I
wanted to talk to him. Has he gone to
hockey practice? Hockey practice is
tomorrow, Dad. Maybe he's gone swimming.
But the pool's closed this week. Oh, I
didn't know that. Perhaps he's gone to
the park to play tennis.
Oh, he's taken his racket. That's where
he is then.
Two. What time will Sam leave home?
The match you're going to see starts at
2, doesn't it, Sam? That's right. But
I'm meeting Ben outside the stadium at
quart. Well, don't you need to leave
soon? It only takes half an hour to get
there, Mom. So, if I go at quarter 2,
I'll still be able to meet Ben at
quarter.
Now, listen again.
The match you're going to see starts at
2, doesn't it, Sam? That's right. But
I'm meeting Ben outside the stadium at
quart. Well, don't you need to leave
soon? It only takes half an hour to get
there, Mom. So, if I go at quarter 2,
I'll still be able to meet Ben at
quarter.
Three. Which animal did Jack see on his
holiday?
How was your holiday in Kenya, Jack? Did
you visit a national park? It was
amazing. Our guide took us to a place
where there are elephants. I was hoping
to see lions, too, but we didn't see
any. Lucky you. I've always wanted to
see wild tigers. Well, you might see
some on your holiday to India next
month.
Now listen again.
How was your holiday in Kenya, Jack? Did
you visit a national park? It was
amazing. Our guide took us to a place
where there are elephants. I was hoping
to see lions, too, but we didn't see
any. Lucky you. I've always wanted to
see wild tigers. Well, you might see
some on your holiday to India next
month. Four. What will the weather be
like tomorrow?
I've put your jacket in your school bag,
Tim. It's going to rain this afternoon.
I'll be okay. Mom, I want you to take
it. I heard on the radio this morning
that it's going to be worse tomorrow.
They say it's actually going to snow.
Really, yesterday it was sunny. I know.
The weather can change so quickly.
Now listen again.
I've put your jacket in your school bag,
Tim. It's going to rain this afternoon.
I'll be okay. Mom, I want you to take
it. I heard on the radio this morning
that it's going to be worse tomorrow.
They say it's actually going to snow.
Really, yesterday it was sunny. I know.
The weather can change so quickly.
Five.
What will Cara eat in the cafe?
I'm ordering a salad for myself. Cara,
what would you like? How about some
pizza or a cheese sandwich? They both
look good. I'll have a sandwich, Dad. I
had pizza yesterday. And do you want a
fruit juice as well? I'm not very
thirsty, but I'd like some of their
lemon cake. I've had it before and it's
delicious.
Now listen
again. I'm ordering a salad for myself.
Carter, what would you like? How about
some pizza or a cheese sandwich? They
both look good. I'll have a sandwich,
Dad. I had pizza yesterday. And do you
want a fruit juice as well? I'm not very
thirsty, but I'd like some of their
lemon cake. I've had it before and it
delicious.
That is the end of part
one. Test four listening part
two. Now look at part two.
For each question, write the correct
answer in the gap. Write one word or a
number or a date or a time. Look at
questions 6 to 10. Now you have 10
seconds.
You will hear a teacher talking to a
group of students about a trip to a
science museum.
Now listen everyone, it's our trip to
the science museum next Thursday. It's
going to help you a lot with your
physics project. And there are a few
things I want to tell you before we go.
You'll need to get to college a bit
earlier than usual. Our bus leaves at
8:30, but you should get here at 8:15,
so we're not late
leaving. When we get there, a guide will
show groups of you around. There are 24
of you going, so I'm going to put you
into four groups of six. You'll see some
interesting exhibitions there. There's a
great one on computer science, but the
really useful exhibition, the one you
must see, is the one called
electricity. You won't need to bring any
money, but I want you to bring a laptop
so that you can make notes. And
remember, if you haven't paid yet, you
need to give me
£750. The museum tickets are £4, but
there's the bus to pay for, too.
Now listen
again. Now listen everyone, it's our
trip to the science museum next
Thursday. It's going to help you a lot
with your physics project. And there are
a few things I want to tell you before
we go. You'll need to get to college a
bit earlier than usual. Our bus leaves
at 8:30, but you should get here at 8:15
so we're not late
leaving. When we get there, a guide will
show groups of you around. There are 24
of you going, so I'm going to put you
into four groups of six. You'll see some
interesting exhibitions there. There's a
great one on computer science. But the
really useful exhibition, the one you
must see is the one called
electricity. You won't need to bring any
money, but I want you to bring a laptop
so that you can make notes. And
remember, if you haven't paid yet, you
need to give me
£750. The museum tickets are £4, but
there's the bus to pay for, too.
That is the end of part
two. Test four listening part
three. Now look at part
three. For each question, choose the
correct
answer. Look at questions 11 to 15. Now
you have 20 seconds.
You will hear Amy and her friend Daniel
talking about going to the cinema.
How was your weekend, Amy? Hi, Daniel.
It was great. My cousin came to visit.
She was tired when she arrived on
Friday, but we went shopping on Saturday
and we saw a film together on Sunday. It
sounds like fun. Well, we nearly missed
the start. The website said it started
at 6:30, but we didn't want to watch the
adverts, so we left home at
quarter. But our bus was late and it
was4 to 7 when we got there.
And were they still selling tickets?
They were. The tickets cost less at the
cinema. They were £10 online. And I got
a 20% student discount, too, so mine was
£8. Ella forgot her student card, so
hers was £10. I didn't really enjoy the
last film I saw. The story was sad, and
I didn't like the music much, but the
worst thing was the actors. Oh, that's a
shame. Well, I enjoyed the pizza I had
afterwards. Was it an expensive
restaurant? Not really. And my pizza was
really good. It arrived quickly, too.
I'll order it again.
Now listen again.
How was your weekend, Amy? Hi, Daniel.
It was great. My cousin came to visit.
She was tired when she arrived on
Friday, but we went shopping on Saturday
and we saw a film together on Sunday.
Sounds like fun. Well, we nearly missed
the start. The website said it started
at 6:30, but we didn't want to watch the
adverts, so we left home
at4, but our bus was late and it was4 to
7 when we got there.
And were they still selling tickets?
They were. The tickets cost less at the
cinema. They were £10 online. And I got
a 20% student discount, too. So, mine
was £8. Ella forgot her student card, so
hers was £10. I didn't really enjoy the
last film I saw. The story was sad and I
didn't like the music much, but the
worst thing was the actors. Oh, that's a
shame. Well, I enjoyed the pizza I had
afterwards. Was it an expensive
restaurant? Not really. And my pizza was
really good. It arrived quickly, too.
I'll order it again.
That is the end of part
three. Test four listening part
four. Now look at part
four. For each question, choose the
correct answer. Look at questions 16 to
20. Now you have 15
seconds. 16. You will hear Ben talking
to his friend about his holiday.
What does Ben still need to pack for his
holiday?
I wish I was going skiing. Ben, have you
finished packing? Almost. I've already
put in some warm sweaters and I'm
wearing my ski jacket to the airport.
What about ski equipment? We're given
that when we arrive, but I think I'll
need something I'll enjoy reading for
the evenings. That's a good idea. Put
something in your bag before you forget.
Now listen again.
I wish I was going skiing. Ben, have you
finished packing? Almost. I've already
put in some warm sweaters and I'm
wearing my ski jacket to the airport.
What about ski equipment? We're given
that when we arrive, but I think I'll
need something I'll enjoy reading for
the evenings. That's a good idea. Put
something in your bag before you forget.
17. You will hear Lisa telling a friend
what she did after college
yesterday. What did Lisa do first?
Did you go out after college yesterday,
Lisa? I was a bit tired and there was a
program I wanted to watch on TV, so I
stayed in. I usually have dinner as soon
as I get home, but I had a college
project to finish, so I did that before
eating. And before I went to bed, I
watched the program I wanted to
see. Now listen again.
Did you go out after college yesterday,
Lisa? I was a bit tired and there was a
program I wanted to watch on TV, so I
stayed in. I usually have dinner as soon
as I get home, but I had a college
project to finish, so I did that before
eating. And before I went to bed, I
watched the program I want to see.
18. You will hear David talking to a
friend about running. What's David's
favorite time of day to go running?
Do you still go running every day,
David? Most days I enjoy it, but I've
stopped getting up early to run. I was
getting tired at college, especially at
midday. But isn't it too dark to run in
the evenings? It's the best time of day
to run. And I run at the sports field.
They've got lights there. That's a good
idea.
Now listen again.
Do you still go running every day,
David? Most days I enjoy it, but I've
stopped getting up early to run. I was
getting tired at college, especially at
midday. But isn't it too dark to run in
the evenings? It's the best time of day
to run. And I run at the sports field.
They've got lights there. That's a good
idea.
19. You will hear Sara talking to a
friend about starting
university. What's Sara going to do in
the year before she starts
university? Are you starting university
this year, Sara? Well, I've decided not
to start until next year. I've had to
read so many books the last few years
that I feel I need a break from
studying. I'd like to travel, but I
haven't got enough money, so I'm going
to look for some office work. It'll make
a nice
change. Now, listen again.
Are you starting university this year,
Sara? Well, I've decided not to start
until next year. I've had to read so
many books the last few years that I
feel I need a break from studying. I'd
like to travel, but I haven't got enough
money, so I'm going to look for some
office work. It'll make a nice change.
20. You will hear Jack talking to a
friend about playing the guitar. What
advice does Jack give his friend?
You play the guitar, don't you, Jack? Do
you have lessons? Lessons with a teacher
are quite expensive, so I practice at
home. Well, what should I do if I want
to learn? There are some good music
books for beginners. That's a good way
to start. Just make sure you practice a
couple of times a week. Okay, I'll do
that. Thanks.
Now listen again.
You play the guitar, don't you, Jack? Do
you have lessons? Lessons with a teacher
are quite expensive, so I practice at
home. Well, what should I do if I want
to learn? There are some good music
books for beginners. That's a good way
to start. Just make sure you practice a
couple of times a week. Okay, I'll do
that. Thanks.
That is the end of part four.
Test four, listening part
five. Now look at part
five. For each question, choose the
correct answer. Look at questions 21 to
25. Now you have 15 seconds.
You will hear Tess talking to a friend
about the things her family enjoy
reading. What does each person enjoy
reading?
Hi, Tess. Can you help me with a college
project I'm doing about the things
people enjoy reading? Yeah. Okay. What
about your family? Your sister likes
comics, doesn't she? That's right. She
loves them. And your mom? What does she
read? She likes reading the newspaper.
She says it's a good way to find out
what's happening in the world. And she
doesn't think blogs are very useful for
that. Ah, what about your brother? He's
always reading computer science
magazines. He thinks they're really
interesting, except for all the
advertisements. He doesn't like those.
And your dad? He writes lots of emails
for work and says that's not much fun.
So in his free time, he loves reading
books, especially ones about history.
Ah, and what does your grandma read? She
listens to the news on the radio, so she
doesn't read newspapers anymore, but
she's just got a mobile phone and enjoys
reading text messages from her friends.
And your cousin? He loves reading his
favorite blogs. He says he doesn't read
books much because it takes too long.
Now listen again.
Hi Tess. Can you help me with the
college project I'm doing about the
things people enjoy reading? Yeah. Okay.
What about your family? Your sister
likes comics, doesn't she? That's right.
She loves them. And your mom, what does
she read? She likes reading the
newspaper. She says it's a good way to
find out what's happening in the world.
And she doesn't think blogs are very
useful for that. Ah, what about your
brother? He's always reading computer
science magazines. He thinks they're
really interesting, except for all the
advertisements. He doesn't like those.
And your dad? He writes lots of emails
for work and says that's not much fun.
So in his free time, he loves reading
books, especially ones about history.
Ah, and what does your grandma read? She
listens to the news on the radio, so she
doesn't read newspapers anymore, but
she's just got a mobile phone and enjoys
reading text messages from her friends.
And your cousin, he loves reading his
favorite blogs. He says he doesn't read
books much because it takes too
long. That is the end of part five.