are five parts to the
test you will hear each piece
twice we will now stop for a moment
before we start the
test please ask any questions now
because you must not speak during the
test now look at the instructions for
part one
for each question choose the correct
answer
one what temperature will the woman use
to cook the
cake I'm going to put the cake in the
cooker now the temperatures at
140° is that in enough that's a bit low
I think 180 is better why don't I put it
in at 160 because I think 180 is too hot
all right I hope it's
good now listen
again I'm going to put the cake in the
cooker now the temperatures at 140° de
is that enough that's a bit low I think
180 is better why don't I put it in at
160 because I think 180 is too hot all
right I hope it's
good
two what did Clara hurt when she played
tennis
hi claraa do you want to play tennis
sorry I played yesterday and I hurt
myself so I can't play today your foot
again you had problems with that last
week as well no I hit my leg with my
racket when I was playing my arms are
stronger than I think I hope you feel
better
soon now listen
again hi Clara
do you want to play tennis sorry I
played yesterday and I hurt myself so I
can't play today your foot again you had
problems with that last week as well no
I hit my leg with my racket when I was
playing my arms are stronger than I
think I hope you feel better
soon
three which photo did the man
take these photos are great thanks but
they're not all mine just the one of the
flowers I'm choosing one to put on the
wall in my new apartment I like the boat
picture best oh I prefer the one of the
birds yes it's nice I've tried to take
photos of birds before but I wasn't
quick enough
enough now listen
again these photos are great thanks but
they're not all mine just the one of the
flowers I'm choosing one to put on the
wall in my new apartment I like the boat
picture best oh I prefer the one of the
birds yes it's not nice I've tried to
take photos of birds before but I wasn't
quick
enough
four which was the woman's favorite
present wow you got lots of birthday
presents yes I'm lucky mom usually gets
me a book because I love reading but not
this time because the one I really like
isn't available yet okay but that jumper
looks nice it is but I'm not sure about
the color anyway this bag from my
sister's the perfect size just what I
wanted now listen
again wow you got lots of birthday
presents yes I'm lucky mom usually gets
me a book because I love reading but not
this time because the one I really like
isn't available yet okay but that jumper
looks nice it is but I'm not sure about
the color anyway this bag from my
sister's the perfect size just what I
wanted
five what did Tom lose
hi Tom you look sad yes I can't find my
mobile I took it to Mark's party last
night I thought it was in my bag with my
wallet when I left but it wasn't is this
it it was under my jacket when I was
leaving I thought it might be yours wow
thank you
now listen
again hi Tom you look sad yes I can't
find my
mobile I took it to Mark's party last
night I thought it was in my bag with my
wallet when I left but it wasn't is this
it it was under my jacket when I was
leaving I thought it might be yours wow
thank you
that is the end of part
one now look at part
two for each question write the correct
answer in the
Gap write one word or a number
or a date or a
time look at questions 6 to 10
now you have 10
seconds you will hear a phone message
about going to play a hockey
match hi Sarah it's Tom I I just wanted
to give you some details about next
week's hockey match against a new team
called
Tigers we usually play on Tuesday but
we're playing later in the week on
Friday that's when everyone's available
next week we're going to their Village
for the match I don't think you've been
there before but it's a good place to
play the village is called ladbury
that's spelled l e d e b u r y write
that down because it's not easy to get
there and you'll need to find it on a
map sorry but there's no bus that goes
to the Village so you will need a car we
can go together oh can you pick up some
drinks for the match I've got all the
equipment we need and Sally's bringing
fruit for after the match please don't
be late meeting at 8:00 p.m. should give
us enough time to practice before we
start playing at
8:45 we'll be home before 10: tired but
happy we won I hope see you next
week now listen
again hi Sarah it's Tom I just wanted to
give you some details about next week's
hockey match against a new team called
Tigers we usually play on Tuesday but
we're playing later in the week on
Friday that's when everyone's available
next week we're going to their Village
for the match I don't think you've been
there before but it's a good place to
play the village is called ladbury
that's spelled l e d b u y write that
down because it's not easy to get there
and you'll need to find it on a map
sorry but there's no bus that goes to
the Village so you will need a car we
can go together oh can you pick up some
drinks for the match I've got all the
equipment we need and Sally's bringing
fruit for after the
match please don't be late meeting at
8:00 p.m. should give us enough time to
practice before we start playing at
8:45 we'll be home before 10: tired but
happy we won I hope see you next
week that is the end of part
two now look at part three
for each question choose the correct
answer look at questions 11 to 15
now you have 20 seconds
you will hear Sue talking to her friend
Peter about a restaurant she went
to it's a pity you couldn't come to the
restaurant with us last night Peter yeah
I wanted to come Sue but I wasn't well
last week and I forgot I needed to
finish some
work how was the restaurant
great I'd like to go there more often
the last time I went there was 2 years
ago the waiter said it's been open for 5
years already and it's so popular that
they had to open a new room a year ago
oh what did you eat the restaurant's
famous for pasta but we all chose Pizza
which was
delicious maybe I'll get the steak next
time it looked good isn't the chef from
Italy actually he's from the
USA and our waiter was Spanish so it's a
very International place I have to go
there come with me I need you to tell me
the best things on the
menu I've only got Wednesday night free
next week but I suppose it's quiet then
so I won't have to book a table
now listen
again it's a pity you couldn't come to
the restaurant with us last night Peter
yeah I wanted to come Sue but I wasn't
well last week and I forgot I needed to
finish some
work how was the restaurant great I'd
like to go there more often the last
time I went there was 2 years ago the
waiter said it's been open for 5 years
already and it's so popular that they
had to open a new room a year ago oh
what did you eat the restaurant's famous
for pasta but we all chose Pizza which
was
delicious maybe I'll get the steak next
time it looked good isn't the chef from
Italy actually he's from the
USA and our waiter was Spanish so it's a
very International place I have to go
there come with me I need you to tell me
the best things on the
menu I've only got Wednesday night free
next week but I suppose it's quiet then
so I won't have to book a
table that is the end of part
three now look at part
four for each question choose the
correct
answer
16 you will will hear a man and a woman
talking about going
shopping what will they
buy are you ready to go into town yes do
you want to try on the coat that you saw
last week I'd rather go another day I'd
like to go to the Bookshop there's a
book I want great I'll come with you to
get the financial magazine I like shall
shall we pick up a pizza for
dinner I'll cook
instead now listen
again are you ready to go into town yes
do you want to try on the coat that you
saw last week I'd rather go another day
I'd like to go to the Bookshop there's a
book I want great I'll come with you to
get the financial magazine I like shall
we pick up a pizza for
dinner I'll cook
instead
17 you will hear a woman leaving a
message for a
friend why is the woman phoning her
friend hi Stephanie I was going to come
round to your place this afternoon I've
got that book I agreed to lend you but
guess what my car's not working so I'll
have to wait for it to be repaired this
afternoon I'm going to the theater after
dinner tonight so we'll have to meet
another time I hope that's okay
sorry now listen again
hi Stephanie I was going to come around
to your place this afternoon I've got
that book I agreed to lend you but guess
what my car's not working so I'll have
to wait for it to be repaired this
afternoon I'm going to the theater after
dinner tonight so we'll have to meet
another time I hope that's okay sorry
18 you will hear a man telling his
sister about meeting someone
yesterday who did he see in
town did you have fun in town I only
went for a
newspaper but do you remember Michael
the man you live next door to not that
Michael the one who was in my class when
I was a kid we were best mates he was in
the shop and we had a good chat he's got
an amazing job as a pilot
cool now listen
again did you have fun in town I only
went for a
newspaper but do you remember Michael
the man you live next door to not that
Michael the one who who was in my class
when I was a kid we were best mates he
was in the shop and we had a good chat
he's got an amazing job as a pilot
cool
19 you will hear two friends making
plans for the
day where do they decide to go
oh what a hot day for a picnic shall we
go to the woods it'll be cooler under
the trees can't we go someplace where we
can go swimming too oh but remember I'm
not a good swimmer I don't feel safe in
the river how about the seaside it's not
dangerous there and we can watch people
sailing oh okay
now listen
again what a hot day for a picnic shall
we go to the woods it'll be cooler under
the trees can't we go someplace where we
can go swimming too oh but remember I'm
not a good swimmer I don't feel safe in
the river how about the seaside it's not
dangerous there and we can watch people
sailing oh okay
20 you will hear a City Tour Guide
giving a
talk why is the museum closed
now this is the national
museum I'm afraid we won't be able to go
inside today which is a Pity because
it's just been painted and looks lovely
you'll notice some roads are closed too
that's because an important visitor's
arriving today the queen she's here on
holiday and is having a private tour of
the museum so we can't go
in now listen
again this is the national
museum I'm afraid we won't be able to go
inside today day which is a Pity because
it's just been painted and looks
lovely you'll notice some roads are
closed too that's because an important
visitor's arriving today the queen she's
here on holiday and is having a private
tour of the museum so we can't go
in that is the end of part four
now look at part
five for each question choose the
correct
answer look at questions 21 to 25
now you have 15 seconds
you will hear Susan talking to a friend
about the sports she
does which sport does she do with each
person
now you do so many different sports
Susan with so many different people you
and your cousin Elias play golf together
don't you yes we did last year but now
we play volleyball together and with
your neighbor Daniel you play tennis
don't you oh Daniel hurt his arm and
can't play tennis anymore so we go
fishing together instead and your friend
Amira does she like sports
yes we've started going to the pool
every week but she's not sure she likes
it she'd like to join a Badminton Club
soon what about Kelly when she's not
playing football we go skateboarding in
the park together do you do any sport
with your brother Ryan yeah he plays a
lot of golf and sometimes I go too he's
teaching me maybe in the future I'll
teach him to be a better swimmer you
should and I saw you going somewhere
with Valerie yesterday were you carrying
tennis
rackets they were too small to be tennis
rackets you saw us with badminton
rackets we're having lessons at the
sports center I love it
now listen
again you do so many different sports
Susan with so many different people you
and your cousin Elias play golf together
don't you yes we did last year but now
we play volleyball together and with
your neighbor Daniel you play tennis
don't you Daniel hurt his arm and can't
play tennis anymore so we go fishing
together instead
and your friend Amira does she like
sport yes we've started going to the
pool every week but she's not sure she
likes it she'd like to join a Badminton
Club soon what about Kelly when she's
not playing football we go skateboarding
in the park together do you do any sport
with your brother Ryan yeah he plays a
lot of golf and sometimes I go too he's
teaching me maybe in the future I'll
teach him to be a better swimmer you
should and I saw you going somewhere
with Valerie yesterday were you carrying
tennis
rackets they were too small to be tennis
rackets you saw us with badminton
rackets we're having lessons at the
sports center I love it
that is the end of part
five you now have 6 minutes to write
your answers on the answer
sheet
e
e e
you have one more
minute
e
e e