Now look at the instructions for part
one.
For each question, choose the correct
answer.
Look at question one.
One.
When is the party?
Are you coming to my birthday party?
>> Yeah. When is it?
>> I wanted to have it this Saturday, the
16th, but my dad's away for work, so I
chose next Saturday instead. That's the
23rd. My birthday is actually on the
20th, but I don't mind.
>> Great. Can't wait.
>> Now, listen again.
Are you coming to my birthday party?
>> Yeah. When is it?
>> I wanted to have it this Saturday, the
16th, but my dad's away for work, so I
chose next Saturday instead. That's the
23rd. My birthday is actually on the
20th, but I don't mind.
>> Great. Can't wait.
two.
What time does the football match begin?
>> Aren't you playing football this
afternoon?
>> Yeah, Dad. I'm going to get my things in
a minute.
>> But it's already 2.
>> I know, but we aren't playing till 3
today. Our teacher can't get there till
quarter.
>> Oh, okay. We can leave home a bit later
then.
>> Now listen again.
>> Aren't you playing football this
afternoon?
>> Yeah, Dad. I'm going to get my things in
a minute.
>> But it's already 2.
>> I know, but we aren't playing till 3
today. Our teacher can't get there till
quarter. Oh, okay. We can leave home a
bit later then.
>> Three.
Which t-shirt would the boy like?
>> I love the picture on that t-shirt, Mom.
>> Oh, is that a lion on the front?
>> I mean, the other one with the
skateboard on it. It's over there next
to the one with the moon on it. Look.
>> Yeah, I really like that. Should we get
it?
>> Yes, please.
Now, listen again.
I love the picture on that t-shirt, Mom.
>> Oh, is that a lion on the front?
>> I mean, the other one with the
skateboard on it. It's over there next
to the one with the moon on it. Look.
>> Yeah, I really like that. Should we get
it?
>> Yes, please.
Four.
How much has the girl paid for each
ticket?
>> I've got the tickets for the school
concert.
>> Great. I'll give you the money tomorrow.
£650. Right.
>> That's right. It's good that my dad
booked them online because you have to
pay more on the day of the concert.
They're £875. Then
>> £225
extra. Huh. That's a lot.
>> Yeah, it is.
>> Now listen again.
>> I've got the tickets for the school
concert.
>> Great. I'll give you the money tomorrow.
£650, right?
>> That's right. It's good that my dad
booked them online because you have to
pay more on the day of the concert.
They're £875 then.
>> £225
extra. Huh, that's a lot.
>> Yeah, it is.
Five.
Who did they have dinner with yesterday
evening?
>> It was great last night. I love it when
someone else joins us for dinner.
>> Yeah, it was nice to spend time with my
classmate Ben.
>> By the way, who was that who picked him
up afterwards? Was it his dad?
>> Actually, it was his granddad. I met him
when I went to their house for dinner.
Now listen again.
>> It was great last night. I love it when
someone else joins us for dinner.
>> Yeah, it was nice to spend time with my
classmate Ben.
>> By the way, who was that who picked him
up afterwards? Was it his dad?
>> Actually, it was his granddad. I met him
when I went to their house for dinner.
That is the end of part one.
Now look at part two.
For each question, write the correct
answer in the gap. Write one word or a
number or a date or a time. Look at
questions 6 to 10. Now you have 10
seconds.
You will hear a teacher talking to
pupils about a school trip.
>> Right. I want to tell you about the
school nature trip which is on the 23rd
of March. Now when we asked you about
the trip a few people wanted to go to
the river but actually the forest was
even more popular and we haven't been
before. So that's where we're going.
Our coach will leave school at 8:45.
So, please get here no later than 8:35.
We don't want anyone to be late, please.
Now, you'll need to think about what to
wear. You'll need a coat to keep warm.
If you wear shorts or anything like
that, I think you'll be too cold.
We'll have a guide. His name's Dan
Pillsy and I'll spell that P I L S E Y
because I'd like you to read about him
online before we go.
He made a great film about monkeys.
You won't see any of those, but try to
find some of the horses which live in
the area. Now any questions?
>> Now listen again.
>> Right. I want to tell you about the
school nature trip which is on the 23rd
of March. Now when we asked you about
the trip, a few people wanted to go to
the river. But actually the forest was
even more popular. and we haven't been
before. So, that's where we're going.
Our coach will leave school at 8:45,
so please get here no later than 8:35.
We don't want anyone to be late, please.
Now, you'll need to think about what to
wear. You'll need a coat to keep warm.
If you wear shorts or anything like
that, I think you'll be too cold.
We'll have a guide. His name's Dan
Pillsy. And I'll spell that P I L S E Y
because I'd like you to read about him
online before we go.
He made a great film about monkeys.
You won't see any of those, but try to
find some of the horses which live in
the area. Now, any questions?
That is the end of part two.
Now look at part three.
For each question, choose the correct
answer.
Look at questions 11 to 15. Now you have
20 seconds.
You will hear two friends talking about
their chess club.
>> I'm glad our teacher told us about chess
club.
>> I already knew about it.
My dad saw an ad in a magazine for it
and said I should join.
>> What do you like about the club?
>> Well, the coach is really good
>> and being in competitions is fun.
>> Only if you win, and I never do.
Spending time with the other players is
the best thing.
>> True.
>> Why didn't you come last week? I went to
see grandma in hospital. She had a
terrible headache, but she's home now.
Tonight, she's helping me with my
history homework.
>> Great.
>> Did you have a good time last week?
>> I played with Alex. I lost, but it was a
good game. I wanted to take some team
photos, but unfortunately, I left my
mobile at home. I missed the bus and
walked home.
>> Oh,
>> are you coming next week?
>> Yes, and I'm going to the cinema
afterwards.
Would you like to come?
>> I have football then, but let's have a
sandwich at the cafe in the shopping
center before that.
>> Okay.
>> Now, listen again.
I'm glad our teacher told us about chess
club.
>> I already knew about it. My dad saw an
ad in a magazine for it and said I
should join.
>> What do you like about the club?
>> Well, the coach is really good.
>> And being in competitions is fun.
>> Only if you win, and I never do.
Spending time with the other players is
the best thing.
>> True.
>> Why didn't you come last week?
>> I went to see grandma in hospital. She
had a terrible headache, but she's home
now. Tonight she's helping me with my
history homework.
>> Great.
>> Did you have a good time last week?
>> I played with Alex. I lost, but it was a
good game.
I wanted to take some team photos, but
unfortunately I left my mobile at home.
I missed the bus and walked home.
>> Oh,
>> are you coming next week?
>> Yes, and I'm going to the cinema
afterwards.
Would you like to come?
>> I have football then, but let's have a
sandwich at the cafe in the shopping
center before that.
>> Okay.
That is the end of part three.
Now look at part four.
For each question, choose the correct
answer.
16.
You will hear a brother and sister
talking.
What does the girl want the boy to do?
>> I'm hungry. Shall we ask mom if we can
have a pizza?
>> Okay. I've just got to finish my
homework first.
>> Do you want help with it? I'm good at
history. Thanks, but it's not hard. Pass
me my phone. I'll check my spelling,
then I'll be ready. I'd love some juice
if you're not doing anything.
>> Okay, hold on a moment.
Now, listen again.
>> I'm hungry. Shall we ask mom if we can
have a pizza?
>> Okay. I've just got to finish my
homework first.
>> Do you want help with it? I'm good at
history.
>> Thanks, but it's not hard. Pass me my
phone. I'll check my spelling. Then I'll
be ready. I'd love some juice if you're
not doing anything.
>> Okay, hold on a moment.
>> 17.
You will hear a girl talking to her
teacher.
What should the girl try to do in the
future?
>> What do I need to get better at next
term, Mr. Howard?
>> You've worked very hard this term, Mary.
Your homework's always been done on
time.
>> Thank you. And you always say something
interesting when we're discussing
things, but sometimes it takes you a bit
too long to finish an exercise.
>> Okay, I'll try to do something about
that.
>> Now listen again.
>> What do I need to get better at next
term, Mr. Howard?
>> You've worked very hard this term, Mary.
Your homework's always been done on
time.
>> Thank you.
>> And you always say something interesting
when we're discussing things, but
sometimes it takes you a bit too long to
finish an exercise.
>> Okay, I'll try to do something about
that.
>> 18.
You will hear a girl talking about her
new bag.
Why did she choose this bag?
Is that a new bag?
>> Yes. Do you like it? I wasn't sure about
getting a green one.
>> So, why did you get it?
>> It was the only one left and the
discount was great. The color's not too
bad, is it? Unfortunately, it's slightly
too small for my books. Maybe it'll be
okay for my swimming kit, though.
>> Now, listen again.
>> Is that a new bag?
>> Yes. Do you like it? I wasn't sure about
getting a green one.
>> So, why did you get it?
>> It was the only one left, and the
discount was great. The color's not too
bad, is it? Unfortunately, it's slightly
too small for my books. Maybe it'll be
okay for my swimming kit, though.
19.
You will hear a girl talking to her
mother.
Why does the girl want to give her
jacket to her cousin?
Can I give my blue jacket to my cousin?
>> The one with the tiny pockets?
>> That's right. I've grown since I got it.
Soon it'll look as if I've borrowed it
from my little sister.
>> Don't you like the color?
>> I do, but I'd like to get a new one.
Probably the same color, though.
>> Now listen again.
Can I give my blue jacket to my cousin?
>> The one with the tiny pockets?
>> That's right. I've grown since I got it.
Soon it'll look as if I've borrowed it
from my little sister.
>> Don't you like the color?
>> I do, but I'd like to get a new one.
Probably the same color, though.
>> 20.
You will hear a boy telling his mother
about a geography lesson.
What did he enjoy most about the lesson?
How was geography today, Nick?
>> Good. We watched a video about deserts.
That was okay. Then we worked in groups
to find out all we could about one
particular desert. Ours was the Sahara.
I drew a map and the others looked
online for information.
It was fun and I felt really proud
because what I did looked great.
Now listen again.
How was geography today, Nick?
>> Good. We watched a video about deserts.
That was okay. Then we worked in groups
to find out all we could about one
particular desert. Ours was the Sahara.
I drew a map and the others looked
online for information.
It was fun and I felt really proud
because what I did looked great.
That is the end of part four.
Now look at part five.
For each question, choose the correct
answer.
Look at questions 21 to 25. Now you have
15 seconds.
You will hear a boy telling his sister
about the activities his friends did at
the weekend.
What activity did each friend do?
>> All my friends were really busy this
weekend. What did Alec do?
>> He finished his school history project.
>> Great.
>> Angela did something more interesting.
She's in a band, so she practiced all
weekend. They use a room above a shop.
>> Oh, yeah. She told me. And what about
Marvin? Doesn't he usually go swimming
at the weekend? Yes, but this weekend he
went away to stay with his granny and
granddad, so he couldn't.
>> What about Diane?
>> She had to go and choose a present for
her dad's birthday, so she went to a
department store.
She wanted to get him some cooking
things.
>> Nice.
>> Gavin visited a castle. It was built in
the 14th century, he said. And they were
lucky because there was a free jazz
concert while they were there.
>> Yeah, he told me. What did Lucy do?
>> Her grandparents were staying at her
house. She wanted to go to the swimming
pool, but her grandmother wanted to play
chess, so that's what they did the whole
weekend.
Now listen again.
All my friends were really busy this
weekend.
>> What did Alec do?
>> He finished his school history project.
>> Great.
>> Angela did something more interesting.
She's in a band, so she practiced all
weekend. They use a room above a shop.
>> Oh, yeah. She told me. And what about
Marvin? Doesn't he usually go swimming
at the weekend?
>> Yes, but this weekend he went away to
stay with his granny and granddad, so he
couldn't.
>> What about Diane?
>> She had to go and choose a present for
her dad's birthday, so she went to a
department store.
She wanted to get him some cooking
things. Nice.
>> Gavin visited a castle. It was built in
the 14th century, he said. And they were
lucky because there was a free jazz
concert while they were there.
>> Yeah, he told me. What did Lucy do?
>> Her grandparents were staying at her
house. She wanted to go to the swimming
pool, but her grandmother wanted to play
chess, so that's what they did. the
whole weekend.
That is the end of part five.