There are five parts to the test. You
will hear each piece twice. Now look at
the instructions for part
one. For each question, choose the
correct
answer. Look at question
one. One. What does Lucy decide to buy?
What do you think of the skirt, Lucy?
Have you tried it on yet? I tried that
on first, Mom, but I'm still not sure if
I prefer the dress. Well, if you can't
decide, how about getting that t-shirt
you saw instead? It's too small. I'm
going to get what I tried on first.
Okay. It looked nicer than anything
else.
Now listen again.
What do you think of the skirt, Lucy?
Have you tried it on yet? I tried that
on first, Mom, but I'm still not sure if
I prefer the dress. Well, if you can't
decide, how about getting that t-shirt
you saw instead? It's too small. I'm
going to get what I tried on first.
Okay. It looked nicer than anything
else.
Two. What time will they meet at the
cinema?
I've got an extra class this evening
that doesn't finish until
6:30. So, can I meet you outside the
cinema later? What time does the film
start? It said4 7 online, but there'll
be 15 minutes of adverts before it
starts. So, if we get there at half,
it'll be fine. Okay. See you then.
Now, listen
again. I've got an extra class this
evening that doesn't finish until 6:30.
So, can I meet you outside the cinema
later? What time does the film start? It
said4 7 online, but there'll be 15
minutes of adverts before it starts. So,
if we get there at it'll be fine. Okay,
see you then.
Three. Which photo are they looking at?
I like this photo of you, Alice. You
look a bit different. Yes, I had my hair
cut short a few weeks after that photo
was taken. And is that your younger
sister, Sarah, standing next to you?
Yes, that's Sarah. She still looks the
same. She hasn't changed much, but she
didn't wear glasses then. I think she
actually looked better with her glasses.
Now listen
again. I like this photo of you, Alice.
You look a bit different. Yes, I had my
hair cut short a few weeks after that
photo was taken. And is that your
younger sister, Sarah, standing next to
you? Yes, that's Sarah. She still looks
the same. She hasn't changed much, but
she didn't wear glasses then. I think
she actually looks better with her
glasses. Four. How far will they cycle
tomorrow?
Would you like to cycle to the lake with
me tomorrow, Jack? That's quite a long
way, isn't it? About 30 kilome. It's
probably only 25 km, but we can go
somewhere nearer if you like. How about
cycling to hillside forest? It's only
about 10 km there and back. Let's do
that. 30 kilome is too far for me. Okay,
see you
tomorrow. Now listen
again. Would you like to cycle to the
lake with me tomorrow, Jack? That's
quite a long way, isn't it? About 30
kilome. It's probably only 25 km, but we
can go somewhere nearer if you like. How
about cycling to hillside forest? It's
only about 10 km there and back. Let's
do that. 30 kilome is too far for me.
Okay, see you tomorrow.
Five. Where is Anna going on holiday
next year?
Did you enjoy your holiday, Anna? It was
great. We stayed on a small campsite in
the mountains. I'm not sure my dad
enjoyed it much. He likes sightseeing,
so he prefers city holidays. Well,
perhaps you can do that next year. My
mom's already booked a hotel by the
beach, so I don't know when dad will get
his sightseeing holiday.
Now listen again.
Did you enjoy your holiday, Anna? It was
great. We stayed on a small campsite in
the mountains. I'm not sure my dad
enjoyed it much. He likes sightseeing,
so he prefers city holidays. Well,
perhaps you can do that next year. My
mom's already booked a hotel by the
beach, so I don't know when dad will get
his sightseeing
holiday. That is the end of part one.
Test three listening part
two. Now look at part
two. For each question, write the
correct answer in the gap. Write one
word or a number or a date or a time.
Look at questions 6 to 10. Now you have
seconds. You will hear some information
on the radio about a competition to win
tickets for a film festival.
We've got an amazing competition for our
listeners, which is to win tickets for a
film festival called the Teen Film
Festival. It's now the festival's second
year. Last year, it was on the 25th of
March, but it's changed to the 18th of
March. That's a week earlier than
before. Five different films are shown
at the festival, all of them 30 minutes
long. The first one begins at 6:45 and
there are some breaks in the evening
with the last film starting at
9:15. Now, we've got festival tickets
for five lucky listeners. To enter the
competition, all you need to do is text
us on
0752463914. It won't cost anything to do
that. In the text message, you need to
say which film you enjoy most and give
us your age and your name, of course.
We'll need that to say who the winners
are. Just make sure you listen to the
program this Thursday. That's when
you'll learn who's won the competition.
But hurry, it's Monday today, so you've
only got a few
days. Now listen again.
We've got an amazing competition for our
listeners, which is to win tickets for a
film festival called the Teen Film
Festival. It's now the festival's second
year. Last year, it was on the 25th of
March, but it's changed to the 18th of
March. That's a week earlier than
before. Five different films are shown
at the festival, all of them 30 minutes
long. The first one begins at 6:45 and
there are some breaks in the evening
with the last film starting at
9:15. Now, we've got festival tickets
for five lucky listeners. To enter the
competition, all you need to do is text
us on
0752463914. It won't cost anything to do
that. In the text message, you need to
say which film you enjoy most and give
us your age and your name, of course.
We'll need that to say who the winners
are. Just make sure you listen to the
program this Thursday. That's when
you'll learn who's won the competition.
But hurry, it's Monday today, so you've
only got a few
days. That is the end of part two.
Test three listening. Part three. Now
look at part
three. For each question, choose the
correct
answer. Look at questions 11 to 15. Now
you have 20
seconds. You will hear Oliver talking to
his friend Noah about a camping trip.
Are you still okay to come camping this
weekend, Noah? Hi, Oliver. Yeah, I think
it'll be fun. Where is the campsite
you've booked? Is it in the mountains?
The one we're staying at in a forest,
actually, about 30 kilometers from the
sea. You've been there before, haven't
you? Yeah, it's nice. They don't have a
pool, and you can't play tennis there.
They don't even have a shop, but
everyone's easy to talk to and they're
great if you need any help. And how are
we getting there? We've got lots of
things to take, so I don't think we can
cycle there or go by bus. I'll drive us
there. Okay, thanks, Oliver. I hope the
weather's okay. They said on the radio
it'll rain for a bit Saturday morning,
but the clouds will go by midday and it
should be sunny in the afternoon. That's
good. Well, I'll go and get a few things
packed. You won't need to bring any
snacks, Noah. I'll bring those. But
don't forget to pack your walking boots.
My brother can lend us his tent. Great.
See you Saturday, then.
Now listen again.
Are you still okay to come camping this
weekend, Noah? Hi, Oliver. Yeah, I think
it'll be fun. Where is the campsite
you've booked? Is it in the mountains?
The one we're staying at's in a forest,
actually, about 30 kilometers from the
sea. You've been there before, haven't
you? Yeah, it's nice. They don't have a
pool and you can't play tennis there.
They don't even have a shop, but
everyone's easy to talk to and they're
great if you need any help. And how are
we getting there? We've got lots of
things to take, so I don't think we can
cycle there or go by bus. I'll drive us
there. Okay. Thanks, Oliver. I hope the
weather's okay. They said on the radio
it'll rain for a bit Saturday morning,
but the clouds will go by midday and it
should be sunny in the afternoon. That's
good. Well, I'll go and get a few things
packed. You won't need to bring any
snacks, Noah. I'll bring those. But
don't forget to pack your walking boots.
My brother can lend us his tent. Great.
See you Saturday, then.
That is the end of part
three. Test three, listening part four.
Now look at part
four. For each question, choose the
correct answer. Look at questions 16 to
20. Now you have 15 seconds.
16. You will hear a man talking about an
art exhibition he went to. Why did he
like the paintings?
What did you think of the art
exhibition, Zach? I'm not really a fan
of modern art. I prefer older paintings,
traditional ones, I suppose. But I went
because a friend said it was amazing,
and I'm glad I went. It's not that the
paintings were beautiful. It's more that
they were different from anything I've
seen
before. Now listen again.
What did you think of the art
exhibition, Zach? I'm not really a fan
of modern art. I prefer older paintings,
traditional ones, I suppose. But I went
because a friend said it was amazing.
and I'm glad I went. It's not that the
paintings were beautiful. It's more that
they were different from anything I've
seen
before. 17. You will hear a man talking
to his friend about his cycling trip.
What was a problem for the man?
How was your cycling trip, Paul? You
didn't get wet, did you? I was lucky. It
was sunny all day and I thought I might
get tired, but I got to the lake and
back, so I was pleased about that. It
sounds like you had a good day. I did,
except I didn't remember to take any
food. It was silly,
really. Now listen
again. How was your cycling trip, Paul?
You didn't get wet, did you? I was
lucky. It was sunny all day, and I
thought I might get tired, but I got to
the lake and back, so I was pleased
about that. It sounds like you had a
good day. I did, except I didn't
remember to take any food. It was silly,
really. 18. You will hear Alice talking
to Chris about a history project they
are doing
together. Why can't Chris do the project
on Wednesday?
We've got to finish our history project
this week. Chris, which day are you
free? Well, it's my brother's birthday
party on Friday, so I can't do it then.
And Rick and I have got tickets to see
our favorite band at City College on
Wednesday.
How about Thursday?
Okay. I've got football practice for an
hour, but I can meet you at
5. Now, listen again.
We've got to finish our history project
this week. Chris, which day are you
free?
Well, it's my brother's birthday party
on Friday, so I can't do it then. And
Rick and I have got tickets to see our
favorite band at City College on
Wednesday.
How about Thursday?
Okay. I've got football practice for an
hour, but I can meet you at
5. 19.
You will hear a teenager talking to her
friend about a science competition she
took part in. How did she feel about the
competition?
How was the science competition, Jess?
You did enter, didn't you? Yeah, my mom
persuaded me to. I wasn't sure at first,
but it was actually a fun day. And the
project that won was really interesting.
It was about helping farmers grow crops.
It taught me a few things I didn't know.
So, I'm glad I went.
Now, listen again.
How was the science competition, Jess?
You did enter, didn't you? Yeah, my mom
persuaded me to. I wasn't sure at first,
but it was actually a fun day. And the
project that won was really interesting.
It was about helping farmers grow crops.
It taught me a few things I didn't know.
So, I'm glad I
went.
20. You will hear two friends talking
about the volleyball club they belong
to. What does the girl like most about
the club?
Hi Laura. Are you coming to volleyball
practice tomorrow? It's at the park this
week. Great. It'll be nice to play
outdoors. Is everyone else coming? Last
week only a few people came. The coach
called everyone to make sure. It's great
she does that kind of thing. Yeah, she's
the best thing about the club really.
Now listen again.
Hi Laura. Are you coming to volleyball
practice tomorrow? It's at the park this
week. Great. It'll be nice to play
outdoors. Is everyone else coming? Last
week only a few people came. The coach
called everyone to make sure. It's great
she does that kind of thing. Yeah, she's
the best thing about the club. Really?
That is the end of part four.
Test three, listening part five. Now
look at part
five. For each question, choose the
correct answer. Look at questions 21 to
25. Now you have 15 seconds.
You will hear a boy talking to a friend
about the activities their classmates
are doing on Saturday. What activity is
each person doing on Saturday?
Hi. Do you know if anyone from our class
is doing anything interesting on
Saturday? What's Leo doing? Oh, he's got
piano practice. What about Emma? Well,
this Saturday she's going to make lunch
for her younger sister while her mom's
out shopping. And Ben, is he watching
the football match on TV? He'd like to,
but he can't because he's got a school
project to finish.
No. What about Sophie? She usually
visits her grandparents, doesn't she?
She's got to go into town to get a new
winter coat. Her old one's too small.
Well, what's Helen doing? She's going to
see her granddad. He hasn't been very
well. And Tim, he's not going for
another bike ride, is he? He went
shopping yesterday and bought a new
computer game. He says it's brilliant,
so he wants to stay at home. He said we
could join him. Great.
Now listen again.
Hi. Do you know if anyone from our class
is doing anything interesting on
Saturday? What's Leo doing? Oh, he's got
piano practice. What about Emma? Well,
this Saturday she's going to make lunch
for her younger sister while her mom's
out shopping. And Ben, is he watching
the football match on TV? He'd like to,
but he can't because he's got a school
project to finish.
Oh, what about Sophie? She usually
visits her grandparents, doesn't she?
She's got to go into town to get a new
winter coat. Her old one's too small.
Well, what's Helen doing? She's going to
see her granddad. He hasn't been very
well. And Tim, he's not going for
another bike ride, is he? He went
shopping yesterday and bought a new
computer game. He says it's brilliant.
So, he wants to stay at home. He said we
could join him. Great.
That is the end of part five.