For each question, choose the correct
picture.
One. Which book does David want to buy?
Look at this book, David. It's about
sailing on the lakes in Switzerland.
>> Oh, wonderful. But I prefer this one.
I'd like to learn to ski next year. I
think I'll buy it.
>> And this book about swimming is great,
too. Look at the photos. Oh, yes. But
that sport doesn't interest me really.
Ellie
>> two.
What size sweater does the girl want?
>> Can I help you?
>> Yes, please. I'd like this sweater, but
you've only got a size 44 here. Have you
got a size 40?
>> I've got that sweater in a size 42.
Or there's this other one in your size.
It's really nice.
>> No, I wanted the other one. What a pity.
>> Three.
What's Robert doing now?
>> Hello, Robert. It's Emma. Are you busy
today?
>> Hi, I am at the moment. I wrote lots of
emails earlier and now I'm reading that
story for my project. Why? Well, I've
got that DVD you wanted to watch.
>> Great. I'll come round in about an hour.
>> Four.
How much will the man's mineral water
cost?
>> I'd like one of those liter bottles of
mineral water, please.
>> Which one? There's Allspring.
That one's €3.25.
or our most popular which costs €3.95.
>> But that other one's only €275,
isn't it? I'll take that one, please.
>> Okay.
>> Five. Where's the magazine now?
>> Have you seen that travel magazine,
Sophie? It was next to the TV.
>> Yes. It's good, isn't it, Dad? I was
reading it in bed last night. There are
some great photos in it. I'll go and get
it.
>> Thanks. I want to take it with me to
read on the train today.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Now, listen again.
One. Which book does David want to buy?
>> Look at this book, David. It's about
sailing on the lakes in Switzerland.
>> Oh, wonderful. But I prefer this one.
I'd like to learn to ski next year. I
think I'll buy it.
>> And this book about swimming is great,
too. Look at the photos.
>> Oh, yes. But that sport doesn't interest
me really, Ellie.
Two.
What size sweater does the girl want?
>> Can I help you?
>> Yes, please. I'd like this sweater, but
you've only got a size 44 here. Have you
got a size 40?
>> I've got that sweater in a size 42.
Or there's this other one in your size.
It's really nice.
>> No, I wanted the other one. What a pity.
Three. What's Robert doing now?
>> Hello, Robert. It's Emma. Are you busy
today?
>> Hi, I am at the moment. I wrote lots of
emails earlier and now I'm reading that
story for my project. Why?
>> Well, I've got that DVD you wanted to
watch.
>> Great. I'll come round in about an hour.
Four.
How much will the man's mineral water
cost?
>> I'd like one of those liter bottles of
mineral water, please.
>> Which one? There's Allspring.
That one's €3.25.
Or our most popular, which costs €3.95.
But that other one's only €2.75,
isn't it? I'll take that one, please.
>> Okay.
>> Five.
Where's the magazine now?
>> Have you seen that travel magazine,
Sophie? It was next to the TV.
>> Yes. It's good, isn't it, Dad? I was
reading it in bed last night. There are
some great photos in it. I'll go and get
it.
>> Thanks. I want to take it with me to
read on the train today.
>> Oh, okay.
Listening part two. For each question,
write the correct answer in the gap.
Write one word or a number or a date or
a time.
You will hear a museum guide giving some
information about a science museum.
>> Thank you for calling the science museum
information line. We have two exciting
pieces of news as well as our usual
exhibitions at the museum. If you visit
us this month, you can see our latest
exhibition which is all about weather.
Do you know where the coldest and
hottest places are in the world? You
will if you visit this exhibition in the
science gallery on the first floor.
Everything you ever wanted to know about
thunderstorms and windy weather. There
are recordings of interviews with the
weather experts and some interesting
videos and photos.
Then come and have lunch in our new cafe
on the fifth floor. Our new menu
includes cakes, sandwiches, salads, and
an excellent variety of teas, coffees,
and cold drinks.
Secondly, we are pleased to say that
there will be a student science quiz
again this year. There should be four
people in each team. So find three
friends who are good at science and
between the ages of 15 and 18.
You can register your team online.
The quiz will be just before the new
September term in the afternoon of
August the 30th. Group discounts are a
listening part two. For each question,
write the correct answer in the gap.
Write one word or a number or a date or
a time.
You will hear a museum guide giving some
information about a science museum.
Thank you for calling the science museum
information line. We have two exciting
pieces of news as well as our usual
exhibitions at the museum. If you visit
us this month, you can see our latest
exhibition which is all about weather.
Do you know where the coldest and
hottest places are in the world? You
will if you visit this exhibition in the
science gallery on the first floor.
Everything you ever wanted to know about
thunderstorms and windy weather. There
are recordings of interviews with the
weather experts and some interesting
videos and photos.
Then come and have lunch in our new cafe
on the fifth floor. Our new menu
includes cakes, sandwiches, salads, and
an excellent variety of teas, coffees,
and cold drinks.
Secondly, we are pleased to say that
there will be a student science quiz
again this year. There should be four
people in each team. So, find three
friends who are good at science and
between the ages of 15 and 18.
You can register your team online.
The quiz will be just before the new
September term in the afternoon of
August the 30th. Group discounts are a
>> listening part three. For each question,
choose the correct answer.
You will hear Paul talking to his friend
Anna about a school trip.
>> Are you coming on Mr. Fox's school trip
tomorrow, Paul?
>> Where?
>> I haven't been in class. I've been ill.
Oh, we're going to meet some
journalists. The ones that write the
sports pages in the newspaper
>> at the stadium.
>> No, in their city office.
>> Are we going there on the underground?
>> It's quicker that way. Yes. I prefer
traveling by bus or coach because you
can look at all the shops on the way.
>> What time are we leaving? I'll be at the
school gates at about 8:20 because my
dad always brings me, but we don't have
to be there until
I don't mind waiting outside for 10
minutes.
>> Okay. Do we have to bring anything? What
about project work?
>> No, but Mr. Fox said bring our mobiles.
He doesn't want to lose anyone. And I
might take a raincoat with me.
>> Right.
>> And we have to pay Mr. Fox £825.
That includes lunch, which is £5.75.
I'm going to take £1 extra.
>> What for?
>> An ice cream.
>> Now listen again.
>> Are you coming on Mr. Fox's school trip
tomorrow, Paul?
>> Where? I haven't been in class. I've
been ill. Oh, we're going to meet some
journalists. The ones that write the
sports pages in the newspaper
>> at the stadium.
>> No, in their city office.
>> Are we going there on the underground?
>> It's quicker that way. Yes.
>> Listening part three.
>> I prefer traveling.
>> Listening part three. For each question,
choose the correct answer.
You will hear Paul talking to his friend
Anna about a school trip.
>> Are you coming on Mr. Fox's school trip
tomorrow? Paul,
>> where?
>> I haven't been in class. I've been ill.
>> Oh, we're going to meet some
journalists. The ones that write the
sports pages in the newspaper
>> at the stadium.
>> No, in their city office.
>> Are we going there on the underground?
It's quicker that way. Yes. I prefer
traveling by bus or coach because you
can look at all the shops on the way.
>> What time are we leaving?
>> I'll be at the school gates at about
8:20 because my dad always brings me,
but we don't have to be there until
I don't mind waiting outside for 10
minutes.
>> Okay. Do we have to bring anything? What
about project work? No, but Mr. Fox said
bring our mobiles. He doesn't want to
lose anyone. And I might take a raincoat
with me.
>> Right.
>> And we have to pay Mr. Fox £825.
That includes lunch, which is £5.75.
I'm going to take £1 extra.
>> What for?
>> An ice cream.
>> Now listen again.
Are you coming on Mr. Fox's school trip
tomorrow? Paul,
>> where? I haven't been in class. I've
been ill.
>> Oh, we're going to meet some
journalists. The ones that write the
sports pages in the newspaper
>> at the stadium.
>> No, in their city office.
>> Are we going there on the underground?
>> It's quicker that way. Yes. I prefer
traveling by bus or coach because you
can look at all the shops on the way.
>> What time are we leaving?
>> I'll be at the school gates at about
8:20 because my dad always brings me,
but we don't have to be there until
I don't mind waiting outside for 10
minutes.
>> Okay. Do we have to bring anything? What
about project work?
>> No, but Mr. Fox said bring our mobiles.
He doesn't want to lose anyone. And I
might take a raincoat with me.
>> Right.
>> And we have to pay Mr. Fox £825.
That includes lunch, which is £5.75.
I'm going to take £1 extra.
>> What for?
>> An ice cream.
>> Listening part four. For each question,
choose the correct answer.
16. You will hear a boy, Andy, talking
to his mother. What's the matter with
Andy?
>> Mom, I don't feel very well. Can I stay
at home today?
>> Yes, you look very tired. Did you eat
any breakfast?
>> No, I've got a stomach ache. I'm not
hungry.
Okay, I'll phone the doctor and ask for
an appointment this morning.
>> Thanks, Mom. I'll text Harry later and
ask him to tell me what homework I have
to catch up on.
>> 17. You will hear a girl talking to her
father. What's the problem?
>> Dad, have you seen my English
schoolwork? It was in my blue project
folder on the sofa.
>> Let me have a look. Um, there are some
keys under the sofa, but no folder.
>> My teacher will be angry if I don't take
it to school.
>> Oh, look. It's in the dog's bed.
>> Rex, you naughty dog. Give it here.
18.
You will hear a woman telling passengers
in an airport about their flight.
How can they find out when it will
leave?
This is an announcement for passengers
waiting for flight AV1 193 from London
to Morca.
This flight will be delayed because
there are storms over this part of the
Mediterranean Sea.
Passengers should check the message
boards for the latest information about
the flight departure before going to the
gate. Please do not go back to the
check-in desks as staff there are very
busy.
19.
You will hear a woman talking to her
son. What does he think about what she's
bought?
Harry, I got something new for you when
I was at the shops today.
>> Is it a computer game? I'd like the new
Race to the Stars game.
>> No, I didn't get that. It's more useful
than a computer game.
>> Oh, it's a lamp. Let's switch it on.
>> Sure. You need one for when you're doing
your homework.
20.
You will hear a boy, Antonio, talking to
a girl. Why did Antonio fail his driving
test?
>> How did your driving test go, Antonio?
>> It was terrible and I failed it. I
nearly hit a cat and had to stop
suddenly.
>> The poor cat. Was it okay? It was. But I
was so shocked I almost drove through a
red light.
>> Oh no.
But you didn't make any mistakes, did
you?
>> Unfortunately, I went the wrong way down
a one-way street, so I have to take it
again.
>> Now listen again.
>> 16. You will hear a boy, Andy, talking
to his mother. What's the matter with
Andy?
Mom, I don't feel very well. Can I stay
at home today?
>> Yes, you look very tired. Did you eat
any breakfast?
>> No, I've got a stomach ache. I'm not
hungry.
>> Okay, I'll phone the doctor and ask for
an appointment this morning.
>> Thanks, Mom. I'll text Harry later and
ask him to tell me what homework I have
to catch up on.
17.
You will hear a girl talking to her
father. What's the problem?
>> Dad, have you seen my English
schoolwork? It was in my blue project
folder on the sofa.
>> Let me have a look. Um, there are some
keys under the sofa, but no folder. My
teacher will be angry if I don't take it
to school.
>> Oh, look. It's in the dog's bed.
>> Rex, you naughty dog. Give it here.
>> 18.
You will hear a woman telling passengers
in an airport about their flight.
How can they find out when it will
leave?
This is an announcement for passengers
waiting for flight AB193
from London to Morca.
This flight will be delayed because
there are storms over this part of the
Mediterranean Sea.
Passengers should check the message
boards for the latest information about
the flight departure before going to the
gate. Please do not go back to the
check-in desks as staff there are very
busy.
19.
You will hear a woman talking to her
son. What does he think about what she's
bought?
>> Harry, I got something new for you when
I was at the shops today.
>> Is it a computer game? I'd like the new
Race to the Stars game.
>> No, I didn't get that. It's more useful
than a computer game.
>> Oh, it's a lamp. Let's switch it on.
>> Sure. You need one for when you're doing
your homework.
>> 20.
You will hear a boy, Antonio, talking to
a girl.
Why did Antonio fail his driving test?
>> How did your driving test go, Antonio?
>> It was terrible. And I failed it. I
nearly hit a cat and had to stop
suddenly.
>> The poor cat. Was it okay?
>> It was, but I was so shocked I almost
drove through a red light.
>> Oh no.
But you didn't make any mistakes, did
you? Unfortunately, I went the wrong way
down a one-way street, so I have to take
it again.
Listening part five. For each question,
choose the correct answer.
You will hear Peter talking to his
teenage daughter about what he needs to
do next week. What must he do on each
day?
I've got a lot to do next week.
>> Yes. You're going to be busy, Dad. On
Monday, you need to get our tickets.
>> Tickets for what? For the play at the
theater. I can't remember the name.
>> No, the plane tickets for our summer
holiday.
>> Oh, yes. And on Tuesday, I want to get a
table for you to study on after work.
>> Can I come with you? And then we can go
to the supermarket, too.
>> Wednesday will be better for that. It's
always quieter, then. What do you want
to get?
>> Oh, just some fruit and snacks to take
to school. And what about Friday? Aren't
we going to the dentist then? No, we're
going to the dentist next week. I want
to fix my bike that evening so I can use
it at the weekend.
>> Good idea.
>> And on Sunday, I've got to call Bill
about the game at the end of the month.
>> The hockey game?
>> Yes, that's right.
>> Now listen again.
I've got a lot to do next week.
>> Yes. You're going to be busy, Dad. On
Monday, you need to get our tickets.
>> Tickets for what?
>> For the play at the theater. I can't
remember the name.
>> No, the plane tickets for our summer
holiday.
>> Oh, yes. And on Tuesday, I want to get a
table for you to study on after work.
Can I come with you? And then we can go
to the supermarket, too.
>> Wednesday will be better for that. It's
always quieter then. What do you want to
get?
>> Oh, just some fruit and snacks to take
to school. And what about Friday? Aren't
we going to the dentist then?
>> No, we're going to the dentist next
week. I want to fix my bike that evening
so I can use it at the weekend. Good
idea.
>> And on Sunday, I've got to call Bill
about the game at the end of the month.
>> The hockey game?
>> Yes, that's right.